<dictionary>
  <word> 
	  <name>abtruse</name>
	  <meaning>hard to understand</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When we can recall events from our dreams, they seem abtruse to us</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin abstrudere: to conceal</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>abstruse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>actuate</name>
	  <meaning>to put into motion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When you leave the house, you must tap in a pin code to actuate the alarm</example>
	  <etymology>from the medieval Latin actuare: to carry out</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>actuate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>acuity</name>
	  <meaning>sharpness of mind or of the senses</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The oratory of Barack Obama's speeches reflects his intellectual acuity</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin acuere: to sharpen</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>acuity</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>adage/aphorism</name>
	  <meaning>a proverb expressing a universal truth</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. One of Oscar Wilde's best-known aphorisms/adages is: 'a little sincerity is a dangerous thing, and a great deal of it is absolutely fatal'</example>
	  <etymology>adage derives from the Latin adagium: a saying (based on an early form of aio: I say); aphorism from the Greek aphorismos: a definition</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>adage</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>adduce</name>
	  <meaning>to cite by way of evidence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Mark Twain passed on investing in Alexander Bell's telephone, wrongly adducing that static on the line would mean no one would buy the device</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin adducere, from ad: toward, and ducere: to lead</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>adduce</pronunciation>
  </word>
   <word> 
	  <name>adjunct</name>
	  <meaning>a thing added to something else but not as a non-core part</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Women find that more attention from men is an adjunct to breast augmentation</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ad: to, and jungere: to join</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>adjunct</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>adjutant</name>
	  <meaning>a deputy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To show he was serious about his government being a coalition, Conservative David Cameron appointed Liberal Democrat Nick Clegg as his adjutant</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin adjuvare: to assist</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>adjutant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>aegis</name>
	  <meaning>the protection of a particular body</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. George Bush Snr was forced to punish Saddam from attacking Kuwait because Kuwait is under the aegis of the US</example>
	  <etymology>According to The Iliad, the aegis (or aigis in Greek) was the shield wielded by Zeua, the king of gods. From the shield hung one hundred golden tassels, which were depicted by Classical vase-painters as writhing snakes. Today, we continue to use the word aegis to denote any protection afforded to one person by another and it is often used to describe one country's looking after another in the international arena.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>aegis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>agent provocateur</name>
	  <meaning>a person who seeks to harm another by provoking them to commit an unlawful or wrong act</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the film Donnie Brasco, Johnny Depp plays an FBI agent who infiltrates the Mafia and encourages their criminality; Depp is an agent provocateur</example>
	  <etymology>from the French agent provocateur: inciting agent</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>agent-provocateur</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>alabaster</name>
	  <meaning>smooth and white</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Nicole Kidman's ginger locks contrast with her alabaster skin</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin alabaster: a perfume casket made from the mineral alabaster; alabaster literally means 'resembling disaster, a white variety of gypsum'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>alabaster</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>aleatory</name>
	  <meaning>random</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Travelling across London at the weekend can be a somewhat aleatory experience in view of the improvement works on the underground</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin alea: a game of dice (singular of 'die'); aleatory literally means 'depending on the toss of a die'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>aleatory</pronunciation>
  </word>
 <word> 
	  <name>amanuensis</name>
	  <meaning>an assistant to an artist</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Agatha Christie had difficulty with writing and spelling owing to a learning disability so dictated all her detective stories to an amanuensis</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin (servus) a manu: (slave) at hand (writing), and ensis: belonging to</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>amanuensis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>amulet</name>
	  <meaning>a small piece of jewellery thought to ward off evil</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After breaking up with his fiancée, James Dean wore an enamel locket containing strands of her hair: this was his lucky amulet</example>
	  <etymology>Examples of amulets include gems, rings and coins; all these objects are small enough to carry around and are believed to bring good luck to the bearer. Amulets also exist in larger form and perhaps the most famous amulet is the crucifix, which is found in the homes of Christians to protect against evil</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>amulet</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anachronistic</name>
	  <meaning>very old-fashioned</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Tower of London is guarded by Beefeaters who dress anachronistically.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anakhronismos, from ana: backward, and khronos: time; anachronistic literally means appropriate to a different time.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anachronistic</pronunciation>	  
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anaemic</name>
	  <meaning>lacking in vigour</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Compared with Rita Hayworth and other voluptuous stars of the day, Grace Kelly appeared anaemic.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anaemia, from an: without, and haima: blood; anaemic literally means 'suffering from anaemia'; this is a medical condition caused by a deficiency of red blood cells, resulting in paleness and weakness.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anaemic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anodyne</name>
	  <meaning>not contentious, often deliberately so</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Great Gatsby author F. Scott Fitzgerald didn't believe in anodyne entrances, once turning up to a Hollywood party on all fours and barking.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anodunos: painless, from an: without, and odune: pain</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anodyne</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anomic</name>
	  <meaning>lacking normal ethical standards</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Serial killer Fred West murdered people on a whim; he was an anomic individual.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anomos: lawless</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anomic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>antediluvian</name>
	  <meaning>so old-fashioned as to be ridiculous</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Critics of the Catholic Church view the refusal to ordain woman as antediluvian.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ante: before, and diluvium: flood. antediluvian literally means 'from a time before the flood created by God to punish man'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>antediluvian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anthropogenic</name>
	  <meaning>created by humans</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The ozone is shrinking due to anthropogenic carbon dioxide emissions.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anthropos: human being and genic: produced by.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anthropogenic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>anthropomorphise</name>
	  <meaning>to attribute human form to something not human, such as an animal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Humans like watching dogs open doors with their paws - as though they had hands - because we like to anthropomorphise animals.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek anthropos: human being, and morphe: form</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>anthropomorphise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>apocryphal</name>
	  <meaning>of dubious authenticity, but relayed as if true (and having the ring of truth)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Although it is true that he declared himself Emperor, the story that Napoleon performed the coronation himself is apocryphal - this duty went to Pope Pius VII.</example>
	  <etymology>apocryphal from the Greek noun Apocrypha, which means 'having been hidden away'. The early Christian Church gave this label to religious writings considered useful but not inspired by God - hence these volumes were excluded from the accepted canon of scripture. Today, when we label a story apocryphal, it means we are casting doubt on its authenticity.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>apocryphal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>apologist</name>
	  <meaning>a person who defends a cause that people find controversial</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Apologists for Nazism are treated with contempt by most people.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek apologizesthai: to give an account.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>apologist</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>apostatise</name>
	  <meaning>to abandon a religious or political belief</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In some interpretations of sharia law, Muslims who have apostatised deserve death.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek apostates: a runaway slave.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>apostatise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>apparatchik</name>
	  <meaning>an official in a huge organisation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Within the Conservative Party, George Osborne is no mere apparatchik, for he is one of David Cameron's closest advisers and the Chancellor.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Russian, apparat: apparatus, and chik: denoting agent.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>apparatchik</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>apposite</name>
	  <meaning>appropriate</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It is apposite to wear black to a funeral.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin appositus, past participle of apponere: to apply (from ad: toward, and ponere: to put)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>apposite</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>approbation</name>
	  <meaning>approval</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bill Gates' donates of billions to charity was greeted with global approbation.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin approbare: to approve.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>approbation</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Arcadian</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a paradise in the country</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many town-dwellers dream of leading Arcadian existence.</example>
	  <etymology>Arcadia is in Greek mythology the home of Pan, the god of flocks and herds; hence today the use of the word Arcadia to signify a rural paradise. (Incidentally, the god Pan gives us another word derived from his name: panic. This is because the Greeks represented Pan as being frightening in appearance - having the horns and legs of a goat but a man's body - which caused anyone who saw him to panic).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>arcadian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>arcane</name>
	  <meaning>shut off to outsiders, hence mysterious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To a Christian, the customs of a Muslim wedding ceremony - such as the elaborate decorating of the bride's hands and feet with henna seems arcane.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin arca: a chest, from arcere: to shut up.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>arcane</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>archipelago</name>
	  <meaning>islands grouped together; OR a sea containing islands grouped together</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The West Indies form an archipelago lying between the Caribbean Sea and the Atlantic Ocean.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek arkhi: chief, and pelagos: sea</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>archipelago</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>argot</name>
	  <meaning>the slang of a particular clique</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The police are called 'the pigs' in the argot of criminals.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French argot: slang</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>argot</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>arriviste</name>
	  <meaning>an ambitious person who has recently 'made it'</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who have inherited wealth regard people whose wealth derives from their own endeavours as arrivistes.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French arriver: to arrive</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>arriviste</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>assiduous</name>
	  <meaning>very diligent</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Conspiracy theorists say the disappearance of the phone records for Marilyn Monroe's flat on the night of her death is evidence of an assiduous cover-up.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin assidere: to be engaged in doing.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>assiduous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>atavistic</name>
	  <meaning>concerning the re-emergence of traits that had disappeared generations ago</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A human foetus starts life with a tail; but as the foetus grows this atavistic feature drops off.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin atavus: forefather.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>atavistic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>attrition</name>
	  <meaning>the process to slowly reducing the strength of someone or something by pressure over time</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. By continually returning the ball, Rafael Nadal wears out his opponent by a process of attrition.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin atterere: to rub.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>attrition</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Augean</name>
	  <meaning>needing so much effort to finish as to seem impossible</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After overthrowing Saddam Hussain, President Bush faced the Augean task of establishing a democracy in Iraq.</example>
	  <etymology>Augean derives from the name of King Augean, who was best known in Greek mythology for his stables, which held the biggest herd of cattle in the country. These cattle were so strong and healthy - in fact divinely so - that they produced huge heaps of dung every day, meaning that no one could ever clean out the stables properly. One of Hercule's 12 labours was to make these stables clean in just 24 hours; he succeeded in this by diverting the path of two rivers into the buildings, thus sweeping away the excrement. Today we continue to refer to any task that seems impossible as Augean.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>augean</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>(auspices) under the auspices of</name>
	  <meaning>with the protection of</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Russia invaded Georgia, the UN objected because Georgia falls under the auspices of the UN.</example>
	  <etymology>The expression under the auspices of derives from the Latin auspicium, which means an observation by a soothsayer who relied on the flight of birds to divine the future. Auspicium itself derives from the Latin words avis: a bird, and specere: to observe.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>auspices</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>autocrat</name>
	  <meaning>someone who demands total obedience from other people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Idi Amin was an autocrat who ruled Uganda with an iron rod, tolerating no dissent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek autokrates, from autos: self, and kratos: power; an autocrat literally means 'a ruler who has absolute power'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>autocrat</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>autodidact</name>
	  <meaning>a self-taught person</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. He left school with no qualifications, became an autodidact and now lectures the world over Italian art.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek autodidaktos: self-taught, from autos: self, and didaktos: taught.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>autodidact</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>automaton</name>
	  <meaning>a person who seems to behave in a way that is more mechanical than human</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Author Virgina Woolf drowned herself by putting stones into her pockets and walking calmly into a river like an automaton.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek automatos: acting of itself, from autos: self, and matos: willing.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>automaton</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bacchanalian</name>
	  <meaning>characterised by drunkenness and partying</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After success in Hollywood, Marilyn Monroe developed an addiction to pills and Don Perignon; hers was a bacchanalian lifestyle.</example>
	  <etymology>bacchanalian originates from the name of Bacchus, a Roman god. Bacchus was at first the god of fertility in nature and was thus at the centre of wild religious ceremonies; later Bacchus continued this association with abandonment by being known as the god of wine who reduced inhibitions and promoted creativity in the arts. (Bacchus was the name given by the Romans to the Greek God Dionysus, see Dionysian)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bacchanalian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>badinage</name>
	  <meaning>witty talk</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Queen Mother used to enjoy a nightly gin and tonic along with some badinage.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French badiner: to joke.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>badinage</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bathetic</name>
	  <meaning>relating to an anticlimax</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. 'Does nobody understand?' were the final words of novelist James Joyce: a bathetic last statement for such a master of communication.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek bathos: depth</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bathetic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>beetle-browed</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person's eyebrows) shaggy and projecting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Old men who do not trim their eyebrows become beetle-browed</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English beetle, and brow, which meant 'eyebrow' (not 'forehead' as it does today).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>beetle-browed</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>behemoth</name>
	  <meaning>a huge thing, especially an enormous organisation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jonathan Ross was one of the highest-paid employees of the behemoth that is the BBC.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Hebrew, behemoth: beast</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>behemoth</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bellicose</name>
	  <meaning>eager to fight</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ghengis Khan's bellicose nature led to conquests that created one of the largest empires in history.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin bellicus: pertaining to war.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bellicose</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>benighted</name>
	  <meaning>ignorant due to a lack of education</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The credit crunch began when onerous mortgages issued to financially benighted families in America went unpaid.</example>
	  <etymology>from the 16th century English benight: cover in darkness.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>benighted</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bifurcate</name>
	  <meaning>to split up into two branches</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. By day Dr Jekyll was a model citizen but at night he turned into the monstrous Mr Hyde: the man led a bifurcated life.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin bifurcus: two-forked, from bi: two, and furca: fork.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bifurcate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>billous</name>
	  <meaning>full of spite</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rock Hudson's agent arranged for the star to marry his secretary so that the press would not direct billous comments towards Rock about his homosexuality.</example>
	  <etymology>billous derives from the Latin billis, meaning 'bile', which is a bitter fluid emitted by the liver to aid digestion; the ancient Greeks believed that bile had a negative influence on someone's mood (hence our use of the word billous today to signify a bad-tempered person). Note that the word billous has the following extra meanings: (of a person) feeling sick; (of a colour) so vivid as to be sickly</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bilious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bilk</name>
	  <meaning>to take money (from someone) using deceitful methods</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The young Errol Flynn was sacked from his jock as a clerk when he bilked money from petty cash to bet on a horse.</example>
	  <etymology>bilk is a variant of 'balk'; a mid 17th-century English word meaning 'to spoil one's opponent's score in the card game cribbage'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bilk</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bipartisan</name>
	  <meaning>involving the agreement of two political parties usually at loggerheads</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The creation of animal-human hybrid embryos for scientific research received bipartisan support from the then opposing leaders David Cameron and Gordon Brown.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin bi: two, and partire: to part</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bipartisan</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>blandishment</name>
	  <meaning>a pleasant utterance to persuade someone to do something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Fidel Castro persuaded Graham Greene to campaign on his behalf against the US government by directing blandishments towards the writer.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin blandus: soft, smooth; from blandiri: to flatter</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>blandishment</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>boulevardier</name>
	  <meaning>a socialite who is well-off and fashionable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With a long list of celebrity friends, hotel heiress Paris Hilton is a noted boulevardier.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French boulevardier: a person who frequents boulevards (which are wide city streets lined with trees, commonly found in the most gentrified areas).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>boulevardier</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bowdlerise</name>
	  <meaning>to cut off material considered unsuitable (from a work), especially with the result that the work becomes less powerful</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The censors bowdlerised the film The Texas Chainsaw Massacre before clearing it for release.</example>
	  <etymology>bowdlerise derives from the name of Dr Thomas Bowdler (1754-1825), who in 1818 published a severely edited version of Shakespeare. As he lived in a prudish age, Bowdler knew that there would be a market for a sanitised version of Shakespeare's work - a version suitable for women and children. Bowdler called his work 'The Family Shakespeare' and it was a big success. Today, we continue to refer to any work of art that has been pared down by a censor as being bowdlerised.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bowdlerise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>braggadocio</name>
	  <meaning>boasting and swaggering</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his last film, The Misfits, Clark Gable insisted on doing hos own stunts, including being dragged by a horse; this braggadocio led to a fatal heart attack.</example>
	  <etymology>braggadocio derives from the name of Braggadocchio, a character in a poem called The Fairie Queen that was published in 1590 by Edmund Spenser to celebrate Queen Elizabeth 1. The character Braggadocchio was famous for his boasting and vain nature and we still use the word braggadocio today to refer to any behaviour of this type.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>braggadocio</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bulwark</name>
	  <meaning>something or someone that acts as a barricade</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Cherie Blair found he husband's soothing comments a bulwark against harsh articles by journalists.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Middle High German Bollwerk, from Bohle: plank, and Werk: work; a bulwark literally means 'a defensive wall'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bulwark</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>bumptious</name>
	  <meaning>offensively self-assertive</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Chat show hosts cannot afford to be too bumptious, as they must allow their guests to dominate the conversation.</example>
	  <etymology>from the 19th century, derived from 'bump'; a humerous coinage on the pattern of 'fractious'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>bumptious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>burlesque</name>
	  <meaning>humour resulting from a comically exaggerated portrayal; OR a variety show involving undressing to music</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some comedians make a living out of the burlesque by imitating the voices of politicians.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin burlesco, from burla: mockery</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>burlesque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Byronic</name>
	  <meaning>(of a man) dark and enigmatic in an attractive way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the film Four Weddings and a Funeral, Hugh Grant plays a Byronic lothario.</example>
	  <etymology>Byronic derives from the name of Lord Byron (1788-1824), an English poet famously described by Lady Caroline Lamb as 'mad, bad and dangerous to kow' because of his womanising and risk-loving nature. 	  It is appropriate then that Byron is today best known for his poem Don Juan, which describes the exploits of a serial philanderer; when we use the word Byronic today, we evoke Lord Byron's dangerous air that so enthralled women.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>byronic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word>
	  <name>Byzantine</name>
	  <meaning>(of an administration) highly complex and sometimes devious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Most people find the UK government's tax system to be Byzantine.</example>
	  <etymology>The Byzantine Empire was the name for the Roman Empire between the 4th and 15th centuries AD. The Byzantine Empire was vast and sprawling and hence required a complex system of government, with thousands of different types of bureaucrats, all wearing different hats and outfits to denote their rank; it's no surprise that, in such as competitive environment, the most successful politicians were marked by their deviousness. Today, when we refer to an administration as Byzantine, we evoke this sense of unfathomable complexity as well as the deviousness of its creators.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>byzantine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cabal</name>
	  <meaning>a secret political group</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. On the many occasions that his leadership was under threat, Gordon Brown moved quickly to disband the cabal responsible.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French cabal: society.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cabal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cadence</name>
	  <meaning>a drop in the intensity of the voice at the end of a sentence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. You can listen to Dame Judi Dench for hours because her voice is full of soothing cadences.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cadere: to fall; the collection of notes comprising the close of a musical phrase.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cadence</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cadre</name>
	  <meaning>a small group of people trained for a specific role</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The SAS is an elite cadre of army troops.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin quandrus: a square</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cadre</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>callisthenics</name>
	  <meaning>gymnastic exercises which have as their aims fitness and grace</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The biggest-selling fitness video of all time, Jane Fonda's Workout, shows the actress performing her callisthenics regime.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek kallos: beauty, and sthenos: strength</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>callisthenics</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>callow</name>
	  <meaning>(of a young person) naive</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The 11-year-old Audrey Hepburn carried messages for the Dutch Resistance hidden in her shoes: she looked so callow that the Nazis never suspected her.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin calvus: bald</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>callow</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cant</name>
	  <meaning>language specific to one group of people and looked down on by others; OR a hypocritical sermon</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. At the Oscars, the woman who wins 'Best Actress' usually embarks on an effusive cant that is customary at such events.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cantare: to sing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>carapace</name>
	  <meaning>a protective shell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who are bullied have to develop a carapace in order to survive.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French carapace: a tortoise shell; a carapace is literally 'the hard upper shell of a tutle'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>carapace</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>careen</name>
	  <meaning>to move fast but in an uncontrolled way in one direction</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. James Dean died when a car careened into his own on State Route 46 in California.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin carina: a keel (which is a kind of ship)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>carious</name>
	  <meaning>(of teeth and bone) rotted away</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When talking, Oscar Wilde used to put one hand over his mouth to disguise his carious teeth from his interlocutor.</example>
	  <etymology>1670s, from French carieux (16c.), from Latin cariosus "full of decay," from caries "rottenness, decay"</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>carious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>carnivalesque</name>
	  <meaning>involving a fun and uproarious mix</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After England won the 2003 Rugby World Cup, a carnivalesque atmosphere reigned in London.</example>
	  <etymology>The word carnivalesque is the adjective from the noun 'carnival', which is a period of celebration that takes place in Roman Catholic countries in the weeks before Lent (i.e. January and February). For Catholics, Lent is a time of austerity when luxuries such as meat are renounced - hence the etymology of the word carnival that derives from the Latin carne vale, meaning 'farewell to meat'; as the carnival is the last chance to celebrate and indulge oneself before Lent's rigours. Processions and masked dancers characterise a carnival and when we use the word carnivalesque, we refer to this spirit of celebration.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>carnivalesque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Cassandra</name>
	  <meaning>someone who correctly predicts disaster but whom no one listens to</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. no one would listen to the few economists who in 2007 warned the world was about to enter a recession; but these Cassandras sadly proved only too accurate in their predictions.</example>
	  <etymology>Cassandra was in Greek mythology the daughter of the Trojan king Priam. Apollo took a shrine to the beautiful Cassandra and gave her the power of prophecy. When it became clear that Cassandra did not return Apollo's love, Apollo became angry and turned his gift into a curse by causing her prophecies, though still true, to be ignored by everyone. Today, we continue to describe as a Cassandra anyone who correctly predicts a catastrophe - such as the recent credit crunch - but is not listened to.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cassandra</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>caustic</name>
	  <meaning>sarcastic in a particularly angry way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Judy Garland, start of The Wizard of Oz, gave her own mother the caustic title 'the real-life Wicked Witch of the West'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek kaustos: combustible; caustic literally means 'able to corrode organic matter by chemical action'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>caustic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cavalcade</name>
	  <meaning>a formal line of people or objects moving together</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. At Elvis Presley's funeral, the cavalcade included 16 white Cadillacs and one white hound dog.</example>
	  <etymology>A cavalcade literally refers to a procession of people on horseback who gather to commemorate an historical event; the riders often travel huge distances in the process. The etymology of the word cavalcade reflects this equine connection, deriving as it does from the Italian 'cavalcare', meaning 'to ride'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cavalcade</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>caveat emptor</name>
	  <meaning>the principle that it is the buyer alone who is responsible for ensuring that something purchased is of good quality</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When a customer drives of with an old car that has been made to look like a new one, the car salesman thinks to himself: 'caveat emptor'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin caveat emptor: let the buyer beware.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>caveat-emptor</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cerulean</name>
	  <meaning>blue like a cloudless sky</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It is enjoyable to go for a stroll when the sun is bright and the sky cerulean.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin caeruleus: sky blue</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cerulean</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ceteris paribus</name>
	  <meaning>assuming other conditions remain unchanged</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rising unemployment will, ceteris paribus, lead to a weaker economy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ceteris paribus: with other things being the same</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ceteris-paribus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>chicanery</name>
	  <meaning>deception</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Investors did not become aware of Bernard Madoff's chicanery until it was too late.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French chicancer: to quibble</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>chicanery</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>chimera</name>
	  <meaning>a thing that is forever desired but not achievable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Due to our responsibilities to others, we must all accept that absolute personal liberty is a chimera.</example>
	  <etymology>chimera derives from the Greek word khimaira, which was in Greek mythology a monster that had a lion's head, a goat's body, and a serpent's tail. Such an animal does not of course exist in reality - and today chimera retains this sense of something that is an impossible dream that will never become a reality.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>chimera</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>chrysalis</name>
	  <meaning>a stage involving preparation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The young Al Pacino spent a year with two aunts whose deafness forced him to gesticulate; this proved a good chrysalis for his extravagant acting style.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek khrusos: gold (because of the golder colour of the pupae of some species); a chrysalis literally means 'the discarded hard outer case of a quiescent insect pupa of a butterfly'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>chrysalis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cineaste</name>
	  <meaning>a lover of films</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Before writing scripts, Quentin Tarantino worked in a DVD rental store, which was the perfect job for a cineaste like him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French cine (from cinema), on the pattern of enthousiaste: enthusiast.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cineaste</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cipher</name>
	  <meaning>a person who is insignificant</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a constitutional monarch, the Queen does not interfere with the running of government but she does work hard for the country and is no mere cipher.</example>
	  <pronunciation>cipher</pronunciation>
	  <etymology>late 14c., "arithmetical symbol for zero," from Old French cifre "nought, zero," Medieval Latin cifra, with Spanish and Italian cifra, ultimately from Arabic sifr "zero," literally "empty, nothing," from safara "to be empty;" loan-translation of Sanskrit sunya-s "empty." The word came to Europe with Arabic numerals. Originally in English "zero," then "any numeral" (early 15c.), then (first in French and Italian) "secret way of writing; coded message" (a sense first attested in English 1520s), because early codes often substituted numbers for letters. Klein says Modern French chiffre is from Italian cifra.</etymology>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>circumlocutory</name>
	  <meaning>using many words when there is no need</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As standard conversatin with Fidel Castro is reported to last hours because the Cuban leader is so circumlocutory.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin circumlocutio, from circum: around, and locutio: speech.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>circumlocutory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cirrus cloud</name>
	  <meaning>a cloud with threads around it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Einstein had white hair that surrounded his head like a cirrus cloud.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cirrus, a curl</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cirrus-cloud</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word>
	  <name>clarion call</name>
	  <meaning>a call for action</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barrack Obama's election campaign speeches included a clarion call for change.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin clarus: clear; a clarion call literally refers to a blast from a 'clarion', which is a shrill war trumpet.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>clarion-call</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cleave</name>
	  <meaning>to become extremely emotionally involved with (someone)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To fall in love at first sight is to cleave instantly to another person.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English clifian: to stick. Note that cleave has a secondary meaning (which is the direct opposite); to split something asunder, using force.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cleave</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>climacteric</name>
	  <meaning>a period when events of huge significance occur</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The time surrounding the invasion of Iraq was the climacteris of Tony Blair's Prime Ministership.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek klimakter: a critical period.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>climacteric</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>coda</name>
	  <meaning>an ending</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Elvis Presley received more that 19,000 uppers and downers from his doctor during the two years before he died: this was a sad coda to the star's life.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cauda: tail</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>coda</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>compere</name>
	  <meaning>the main presenter of a show, responsible for introducing others</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When his mother's voice gave out, the five-year-old Charlie Chaplin finished her song after being ushered on by the compere.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French compere: a godfather.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>compere</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>concatenation</name>
	  <meaning>a series of things that are linked as if in a chain</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Andy Warhol sometimes produced paintings by having his dog urinate on the canvas; the critics lauded the resulting concatenations of yellow.</example>
	  <pronunciation>concatenation</pronunciation>
	  <etymology>c.1600, from Late Latin concatenationem (nominative concatenatio) "a linking together," noun of action from past participle stem of concatenare "to link together," from com- "together" (see com-) + catenare, from catena "a chain"</etymology>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>concomitant</name>
	  <meaning>a phenomenon that goes hand in hand with something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Diseases such as psoriasis are often concomitants to stress.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin concomitari, from con: together with, and comitari: to accompany (from the Latin comes: companion)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>concomitant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>conflation</name>
	  <meaning>the act of melding two of more ideas into one</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Ben Afleck and Jennifer Lopez were an item, journalists used to refer to the couple by the conflation of 'Bennifer'</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>conflation</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>congeries</name>
	  <meaning>a messy collection</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The competitors on the TV show Big Brother are from a congeries of backgrounds.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin congeries: a heap, from congerere: to heap up.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>congeries</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>congruous</name>
	  <meaning>harmonious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It seems congruous that William Shakespeare dies on the 23rd April - for that is also the day he was born.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin congruere: to agree</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>congruous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>conquistador</name>
	  <meaning>a person who sets out in search of adventure</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Society's double standards mean that promiscuous men are lauded as conquistadors whilst promiscuous women are viewed as sluts.</example>
	  <etymology>conquistador means 'conquerer' in both Spanish and Portuguese. 
	  Today, the term conquistador is used to denote a conqueror of any kind.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>conquistador</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>consigliere</name>
	  <meaning>someone who advises</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Before Henry VIII turned on him and chopped off his head, Sir Thomas More was consigliere to the king.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian consigliere: adviser.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>consigliere</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>continuum</name>
	  <meaning>a continuous sequence in which adjacent elements are very similar to each other, but the extremes are polar opposites</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Alfred Kingsley believed that human sexuality forms a continuum, with complete heterosexuality at one end and complete homosexuality at the other.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin continuus: uninterrupted</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>continuum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>contrail</name>
	  <meaning>the streak of white that a plane leaves behind it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The jet passed overhead, leaving a contrail in the sky.</example>
	  <etymology>contrail is an abbreviation of the 1940s expression 'condensation trail'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>contrail</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>contumely</name>
	  <meaning>insulting treatment</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A judge will not stand for contumely from a witness in court.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin contumelia: an insult, from con: (an intensifying prefix), and tumere: to swell up</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>contumely</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cornucopia</name>
	  <meaning>an overflowing supply of pleasant things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Guests at weddings can expect to be served a cornucopia of food.</example>
	  <etymology>cornucopia means in Latin 'a horn of plenty' (conu copiae); from the 5th century BC, this was a symbol of food and abundance. The following Greek myth explains why it is that a goat's horn has become associated with a surfeit of good things. When the god Zeus was young, he used to play with a goat, whose horn he broke off one day by accident; to make amends, the god returned the horn to the goat, but in an improved form, for it was imbued with magical powers that meant whoever possessed it got whatever they wished for. Hence the horn came to be depicted by the Greeks as bursting with fruits and flowers and other treats that people desired; today we continue to use the word cornucopia to refer to any bountiful display of food and goodies.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cornucopia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>corollary</name>
	  <meaning>something that naturally follows</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who have cataracts in their eyes literally see red: in fact the reddish tone of Monet's paintings is a corollary of his suffering from this condition.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin corollarium: money paid for a garland.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>corollary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>coruscating</name>
	  <meaning>(of light or of humour) sparkling</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. American wit H. L. Mencken once said, 'On one issue at least, men and women agree: they both distrust women'. What coruscating humour!</example>
 	  <etymology>1705, from Latin coruscatus, past participle of coruscare "to vibrate, glitter," perhaps from PIE *(s)ker- (2) "leap, jump about" (cf. scherzo). Related: Coruscated; coruscating.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>coruscating</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>costive</name>
	  <meaning>(of someone's character) niggardly; (of speech or movement) slow</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Henry VIII became obese in his old age and later portraits of the monarch show him looking positively costive.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French costive: constipated (itself derived from the Latin constipatus: pressed together); costive literally means constipated.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>costive</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>coterie</name>
	  <meaning>a small group of people with a common goal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Elvis Presley was accompanied everywhere by the 'Memphis Mafia': his coterie of bodyguards and helpers.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French cotier: an organisation of peasants holding land owned by a feudal lord.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>coterie</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>coup de grace</name>
	  <meaning>a fatal blow that finishes off a wounded animal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. For a discontented wife, the discovery that her husband has been unfaithful is usually the coup de grace for the marriage.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French coup de grace: a stroke of grace</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>coup-de-grace</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>covey</name>
	  <meaning>a small crowd of people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As Tom Cruise arrived at the première of Mission Impossible, a covey of photographers snapped away.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French covee: a brood; a 'covey' is literally 'a small flock of birds'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>covey</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cowlick</name>
	  <meaning>a clump of hair at the back of the head that refuses to be straightened but sticks up straight as licked by a cow</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The hairdo of cartoon character Tintin consists of one giant cowlick</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cowlick</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>crapulent</name>
	  <meaning>nauseous due to overindulgence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The wide girth of the older Marlon Brando spoke of a man who had enjoyed many a crapulent evening.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin crapula: inebriation.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>crapulent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>craven</name>
	  <meaning>so timid as to be cowardly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Charlie Chaplin failed to server in World War 1 - not because he was craven, but because the army rejected him for being too small</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French cravante, past participle of cravanter: to crush</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>craven</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cri de coeur</name>
	  <meaning>a cry from the heart</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Princess Diana's TV interview with Martin Bashir - when she discussed the constrictions of royal life - was interpreted as a cri de coeur by the public.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cri-de-coeur</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cumulus</name>
	  <meaning>a large cloud composed of wispy clouds mixed together</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. On entering the cumulus, the pilot of the helicopter couldn't see a thing.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cumulus: heap</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cumulus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cupola</name>
	  <meaning>a small dome that sits on top of a roof of a larger dome</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Adorning the curved roof of the main dome of St Paul's Cathedral is a celebrated cupola.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin cupula: small cask</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cupola</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>cursive</name>
	  <meaning>written in joined up handwriting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a boy Hitchcock was obsessed with locomotives: the floor of his room was strewn with train timetables copied out in primitive cursive.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin currere: to run</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>cursive</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>de facto</name>
	  <meaning>in fact</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Colonel Gaddafi has been the de facto leader of Libya since a coup in 1969.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin de facto: of fact</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>de-facto</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>defray</name>
	  <meaning>to give money to cover (an expense)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If you are unemployed, the government will pay you a jobseeker's allowance to defray your outgoings.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French defrayer, from de: (expressing removal), and frai: cost</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>defray</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>deleterious</name>
	  <meaning>destructive</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Serial killer Fred West had violent rages, resulting from a motorbike accident that was deleterious to his brain.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek deleterios: noxious</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>deleterious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Delphic</name>
	  <meaning>(of a pronouncement) purposefully unclear</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After being charged for kicking out at opposition fans, footballer Eric Cantona called a press conference to deliver the following Delphic pronouncement: 'when the seagulls follow the trawler, it is because they think sardines will be thrown into the sea'</example>
	  <etymology>Delphic has its derivation in the ancient Greek oracle at Delphi, whose priestess was said to have the power of prediction; however, her pronouncements were so ambiguous that it was very hard to work out what she meant. For example, the oracle once warned a warrior called Lysander to watch out for: 'a serpent...craftily creeping up behind you...'. Lysander was presumably ever alert for snakes after that but in the end was killed by a man who was standing being him at the time and who had a snake on his shield - so the oracle's warning, although truthful in a way, wasn't really helpful. Today we use the term Delphic to evoke any pronouncement that is similarly hard to understand.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>delphic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>demimonde</name>
	  <meaning>a group of people on the periphery of society</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Unlicensed cab drivers form part of the demimonde of illegal workers in the UK.</example>
	  <etymology>demimonde is a French expression meaning 'half-world'; in 19th-century France the term referred to those women who were shunned by society because they lived off their wealthy lovers to whom they were not married. Today, society is more tolerant of such situatios and so the term demimonde no longer refers to women in this position, but continues to be used of people who are on the fringes of society, such as workers who are in the UK illegally.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>demimonde</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>demotic</name>
	  <meaning>relating to everyday languages</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Dan Brown writes forcefully in demotic English and this in part explains the huge success of his book The Davinci Code</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek demotikos: popular</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>demotic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>denouement</name>
	  <meaning>the climax of several actions, when the outcome becomes clear</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Superman always triumphs over Lex Luthor in the denouement of the comic strips.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French denouer: to unknot</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>denouement</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>depredation</name>
	  <meaning>an act of looting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After some would-be blackmailers attempted a depredation of Charlie Chaplin's corpse, his family reburied his body under six feet of concrete.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin depraedari: to plunder</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>depredation</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>deracinate</name>
	  <meaning>to take something by the roots and tear it out; to alienate someone from their natural environment</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Model Claudia Schiffer, who was born in Germany but now lives in England, is always photographed smiling: she never looks deracinated</example>
	  <etymology>from the French deraciner, from de: (expressing removal), and racine: root</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>deracinate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>desultory</name>
	  <meaning>jumping from one thing to another</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The inebriated diner can have difficulty following a desultory dinner party conversation.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin desultor: vaulter, from the verb desilire: to jump down.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>desultory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>deus ex machina</name>
	  <meaning>an event that comes out of the blue and changes the outcome of a story</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the Mel Gibson film Apocolypto, the hero is saved from human sacrifice by the deus ex machine of a solar eclipse.</example>
	  <etymology>deus ex machina derives from the Greek term theos ek mekhane (meaning 'god from the machinery') and referred to those actors who, because they represented gods, were suspended above the stage in Greek theatres. Eventually these actors would be lowered down and intervene in the events on the stage, thus bringing about the plays ending. Today, we continue to use the term deus ex machina to refer to any device that appears from nowhere to end a film, play, or novel.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>deus-ex-machina</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dialectic</name>
	  <meaning>the contradiction between two opposing forces viewed as the determining factor in their continuing interaction</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The tension between the human tendency to sin and the desire for salvation is the dialectic that fascinated novelist Graham Greene.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek dialektike: debate</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dialectic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>diaspora</name>
	  <meaning>the scattering of any people outside their homeland; OR the people who have been thus scattered</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The 21-year-old Arnold Schwarzenegger came to the US in the 1960s: he was part of a diaspora from Europe at that time.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek dia: across, and speirin: to scatter (hence diasperein: to disperse)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>diaspora</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dichotomy</name>
	  <meaning>a contrast between two things that are polar opposites</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bestsetlling authors like John Grisham are used to the dichotomy of being very popular with the public but sometimes unpopular with the critics.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek dikhotomia, from dikho: in two, and tomia: cutting (from temnein: to cut)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dichotomy</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Dickensian</name>
	  <meaning>bringing to mind the novels of Charles Dickens (especially in evoking the themes of poverty and exploitation)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In one Dickensian scene from Roald Dahl's book Matilda, a cruel headmistress beats the girl Matilda</example>
	  <etymology>Dickensian refers to the novels of Charles Dickens, which were works of social commentary, as the author was committed to exposing poverty in Victorian society. The publicity unleashed by Dicken's novel Oliver Twist (1838), for example, led to the eventual dismantlement of a slum called Jacob's Island that was the basis for the story. Today we continue to use the term Dickensian to refer to any work that draws attention to poverty and social inequality.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dictum</name>
	  <meaning>a short statement that expresses a universal truth; OR a pronouncement from an official source</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Warren Beatty is discreet about his romances, citing the dictum: 'Obviously my sex life is not mine alone to talk about'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dictum: something said, neuter past participle of dicere: to say</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dictum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>didactic</name>
	  <meaning>in the style of a patronising teacher</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Readers prefer novels that have a subtly message rather than a didactic ending.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek didaktikos, from didaskein: to teach</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>didactic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>diktat</name>
	  <meaning>an order imposed by a ruler despite objections from his people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Tyrants issue diktats on a whim</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dictatum: something dictated</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>diktat</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dilatory</name>
	  <meaning>slow to take action (often purposefully so)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Alfred Hitchcock was awarded a knighthood but died before the Queen could present it to him because he was so dilatory in arranging to receive it.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dilatorius: delaying</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dilatory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Dionysian</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the realms of sexual and emotional gratification</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Hugh Hefner, owner of Playboy magazine, is known for his parties that the media depict as Dionysian.</example>
	  <etymology>Dionysian derives from the name of Dionysus, who in Greek mythology was the god of wine and ecstasy: hence the word Dionysian today refers to displays of intoxication and sensual indulgence. Note that Dionysus had a brother, Apollo, who was the exact opposite; when we describe someone as 'Apollonian', we mean that they embody Apollo's calm and disciplined nature. (Bacchus was the name given to Dionysus by the Romans)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dionysian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dirge</name>
	  <meaning>a lament for the dead</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. At Michael Jackson's funeral, the mourners were moved to tears by the dirge sung by Stevie Wonder.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dirige! (imperitive): direct!</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dirge</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>disburse</name>
	  <meaning>(of money) to pay out</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The government collects taxes then disburses this money, directing it to public services such as the NHS.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French desbourser, from des: (expressing removal), and bourse: purse</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>disburse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>disport oneself</name>
	  <meaning>to enjoy oneself without inhibitions</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In advertisements for holidays, models are often pictured disporting themselves on sunlit beaches.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French desporter, from des: away, and porter: to carry</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>disport</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>disquisition</name>
	  <meaning>a long speech on a subject</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Martin Luther King was renowned for his public disquisitions on civil rights.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin disquisitio: investigation, based on quaerere: to seek.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>disquisition</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dissemble</name>
	  <meaning>to hide one's true motives</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When someone asks 'How are you?', people who have the flu often dissemble and say 'Fine, thanks' rather than discuss their ailment.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dissimulare: to disguise</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dissemble</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dissimulate</name>
	  <meaning>to hide one's true thoughts</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Faced with a large hotel bill, Errol Flynn feigned appendicitis: he had no compunction about dissimulating.</example>
	  <etymology>1530s, from Latin dissimulatus, past participle of dissimulare "to disguise, hide, conceal, keep secret," from dis- (see dis-) + simulare (see simulate). Related: Dissimulated; dissimulating.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dissimulate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dissipate</name>
	  <meaning>to disappear (via dispersal); OR to cause to disappear</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Once he'd stopped boxing, Mike Tyson found an alternative way to dissipate his energy: by working out at the gym</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin dissipare: to scatter</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dissipate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>distend</name>
	  <meaning>to swell due to a force from inside</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When pregnant with twins, actress Angelina Jolie had a noticeably distended belly</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin distendere: to stretch out, from dis: apart, and tendere: to stretch</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>distend</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>diuretic</name>
	  <meaning>a drug that causes one to pass water more frequently</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Alcohol and coffee are the most commonly used diuretics</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek dia: through, and ouron: urine (hence diourein: to urinate)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>diuretic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>doctrinaire</name>
	  <meaning>stubbornly insisting on applying a doctrine</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Detractors of the Catholic Church say it is doctrinaire in sexual matters.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin doctrina: teaching, from docere: to teach</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>doctrinaire</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Doric</name>
	  <meaning>relating to classical order of architecture, characterised by a thick grooved column, topped by a rounded moulding and then a square</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the grounds of English country estates, you often find streams with Doric temples nearby</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek Dorios: of Doris; which refers to the people of Doris who entered central Greece from the north in c.1100BC, and later colonised southern Italy.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>doric</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>doublethink</name>
	  <meaning>the ability to simultaneously believe in two ideas that contradict each other, while wilfully ignoring this contradiction</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Critics say the Chinese government's statement - that 'China's internet is open and managed in accordance with the law' - is an example of doublethink.</example>
	  <etymology>doublethink is a concept invented by George Orwell in his novel Nineteen Eighty-Four.
	  Nineteen Eighty-Four describes a totalitarian government which exercises control over its subject via propaganda. Yet the risk remains for the ruling regime that the disgust felt by its own officials at this use of propaganda might lead to the collapse of the system. This is the reason that the ruling regime uses reality control to ensure everyone - even its own officials - remains wilfully ignorant of contradictions within the regime's use of propaganda. One of the reality control devices that officials are encouraged to use is doublethink, which, Orwell tells us, is the ability to hold 'two contradictory beliefs in one's mind simultaneoulsy' while believing both to be correct. An example in the book is when civil servants rewrite government history and are then able to believe wholeheartedly in this new version of history that they themselves have just created. Today, we use the work doublethink to refer to any instance of someone wilfully ignoring contradictions in a belief system.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>doublethink</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dovish</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) advocating peace</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ghandi did so much to promote peace that he is still considered the most dovish politician of all time.</example>
	  <etymology>dovish is an adjective deriving from 'dove', which is traditionally seen as a bird of peace due to its white feathers and cooing voice; hence, for example, the Christian faith's depiction of the Holy Spirit as a dove. Today, when we call someone dovish, we mean that person advocates peaceful policies in foreign affairs.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ductile</name>
	  <meaning>able to be guided</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bing Crosby used to pin back his cauliflower ears with gum; his ears were sufficiently ductile to allow this.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ductilis, from duct: led (from the verb ducere: to lead)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ductile</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dyad</name>
	  <meaning>two individuals that are viewed as a pair</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Psychologists spend much time discussing the parent-child dyad.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek duas: two</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dyad</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dyspeptic</name>
	  <meaning>having indigestion; OR having the irritability that results from indigestion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After a ten-course meal, most people look dyspeptic</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek duspeptos: difficult to digest</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dyspeptic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>dystopia</name>
	  <meaning>an imagined place that is nightmarish</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his documentary film An Inconvenient Truth, Al Gore warns us that we face dystopia unless we arrest global warming.</example>
	  <etymology>"imaginary bad place," 1868, apparently coined by J.S. Mill ("Hansard Commons"), from Greek dys- "bad, abnormal, difficult" (see dys-) + utopia. Related: Dystopian.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>dystopia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>edict</name>
	  <meaning>an order from someone in office</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. 'Drink to me, drink to my health - you know I can't drink any more' was the last edict uttered by Pablo Picasso to his friends before he died.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin edicere, from e: out, and dicere: to say, tell</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>edict</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>effluent</name>
	  <meaning>waste in liquid form that is emitted into a river</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Effluent from factories contaminates rivers</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin effluere: to flow out</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>effluent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>effulgent</name>
	  <meaning>(of a light) shining strongly; OR (or a person's expression) emanating happiness</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Mother Theresa's kindness found expression in her efulgent face</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin effulgere: to shine brightly, from ex: out, and fulgere: to shine</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>effulgent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>egalitarian</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the premise that all people are equal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Social activists press for an egalitarian society</example>
	  <etymology>from the French egal: equal</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>egalitarian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>egregious</name>
	  <meaning>so bad as to stand out</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In September 1955, James Dean died from egregious injuries sustained in a car crash: his head was almost severed from his body.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin e: out, and grex: flock; egregious literally means 'standing out from the flock because the thing being described is so bad'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>egregious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>eldorado</name>
	  <meaning>an imaginary place full of gold sought in South America by 16th-century explorers; OR a lifelong goal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the 19th century, many Europeans left to settle in the US, which they viewed as eldorado</example>
	  <etymology>eldorado - which means 'the golden one' (El Dorado) in Spanish - refers to a mythical city of gold that the 16th-century Spanish conquistadors were told existed in the newly discovered Americas.   Spurred on by assurances from captive Indians that El Dorado overflowed with gold and precious gemstones, groups of Spaniards went out to find this place - but in vain, with many of them dying from diseases and attacks by the natives. Today, we use the word eldorado to signify a place where wealth can be acquired quickly (doubtless the founders of the world's biggest websites would describe the Internet as an eldorado). Eldorado can also be used to refer to a lifelong ambition (as as attaining happiness) and, in this way, it is similar to the word Shangir-La.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>elagiac</name>
	  <meaning>(of a work of art) like a lament</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The film Schindler's List, which covers the atrocities committed by the Nazis, has an elegiac tone.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>elegiac</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>elliptical</name>
	  <meaning>(of speech) lacking key words (but the sense can be worked out from the context)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the film ET, it is easy to understand phrases such as 'ET go home' even though they are elliptical.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek elleiptikos: defective, from elleipein: to leave out.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>elliptical</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>elucidate</name>
	  <meaning>to explain (something) clearly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his book A Brief History Of Time (1988), Stephen Hawking uses simple language to elucidate the subject of black holes.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin elucidare: to make clear, from e: out, and lucidus: light</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>elucidate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>emaciated</name>
	  <meaning>to be unusually lean</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Due to a meagre diet most homeless people look emaciated.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin emaciare, from e (expressing a change of state), and macies: leanness</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>emaciated</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>embonpoint</name>
	  <meaning>plumpness of person</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Towards the end of his life Marlon Brando grew depressed and his embonpoint increased dramatically.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French en bon point: in good condition; embonpoint is a euphemism for fatness</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>embonpoint</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>emetic</name>
	  <meaning>a substance that brings about vomiting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The emperor Nero tried to keep his weight down by using emetics.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek emein: to vomit</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>emetic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>eminence grise</name>
	  <meaning>a person who wields considerable power even through they have no official role</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Tony Blair was in power, the media depicted his unelected adviser Alistair Campbell as the eminence grise of the Labour Party.</example>
	  <etymology>eminence grise is a French expression literally meaning 'grey eminence'. The reason we use this term to describe a person who exerts a powerful but behind-the-scenes influence is because the first example of the controlling types to which this word refers was the grey-cloaked Pere Jospeh (1577-1638), who was the private secretary who controlled Cardinal Richelieu (who himself controlled King Louis XIII, the nominal ruler of France).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>eminence-grise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>endemic</name>
	  <meaning>characteristic of people belonging to one particular area</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Roget Federer epitomises the cool precision endemic to the Swiss.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek endemos: native, based on demos: people</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>endemic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>enervate</name>
	  <meaning>to weaken (someone)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People involved in even minor car crashes feel enervated for weeks afterwards.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin enervare: to weaken (by extraction of the sinews)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>enervate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>emnity</name>
	  <meaning>hostility towards someone or something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When somebody accused him of being a vandal because he was signing copies of his own novels in a bookshop, Stephen King felt no emnity; he knew it was a simple misunderstanding.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin inimicus: enemy</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>enmity</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ennui</name>
	  <meaning>the kind of dissatisfaction that arises when nothing exciting has happened for a while</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Teenagers are moody because the chemical changes in their bodies ensure the feel ennui more than the rest of us.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French ennui: boredom</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ennui</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ephemeron</name>
	  <meaning>something that is short-lived</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Charlie Chaplin is still well-known today: his fame was no ephemeron</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek ephemeros: lasting only a day</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ephemeron</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>epithet</name>
	  <meaning>a phrase that describes someone</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his body-building days, Arnold Schwarzenegger's powerful physique meant that he was known by the epithet of 'The Austrian Oak'</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek epitheton, neuter of epithetos: attributed</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>epithet</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>eponymous</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) giving their name to something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the TV series Columbo, Peter Falk played the eponymous here detective</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek epic: upon, and onyma, variant of onoma: name</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>eponymous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ersatz</name>
	  <meaning>used as a poor substitute (for something else)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After his marriage to Marilyn Monroe ended, baseball star Joe DiMaggio pursued lookalikes of his wife; but he found no joy with these ersatz Marilyns.</example>
	  <etymology>875, from German Ersatz "units of the army reserve," literally "compensation, replacement, substitute," from ersetzen "to replace," from Old High German irsezzen, from ir-, unaccented variant of ur- + setzen "to set" (see set (v.)). As a noun, from 1892.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ersatz</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ethereal</name>
	  <meaning>so delicate as to seem otherworldly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With her thin frame and light hair, Michelle Pfeiffer emits an ethereal impression.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek aither: the upper air</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ethereal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>etiolated</name>
	  <meaning>looking sickly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Brazilian beauty who calls herself Giselle has curves, differentiating her from the average etiolated supermodel.</example>
	  <etymology>etiolated was first used to refer to a plant that has become sickly and drawn-looking due to a lack of exposure to light. The word etiolated then evolved to describe humans in a similarly enfeebled state.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>etiolated</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>euphonic</name>
	  <meaning>sounding good</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Elton John is rich because he has produced a series of highly euphonic melodies over the years and these have sold well.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek eu: well, and phone: sound</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>euphonic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>evanescent</name>
	  <meaning>vanishing fast</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The four members of the pop group ABBA got married and then divorced; but sadly these two unions proved to be evanescent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin evanescere: to disappear</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>evanescent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>eviscerate</name>
	  <meaning>to take away the core of something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Director Stanley Kubric was upset when is film A Clockwork Orange was eviscerated by the censors.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin eviscere: to disembowel, from e: out, and viscera: internal organs</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>eviscerate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>excoriate</name>
	  <meaning>to criticise strongly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Peter Sutcliffe, the Yorkshire Ripper, is excoriated for his horrific murders of women.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin excoriare: to skin, from ex: out, and corium: skin; excoriate literally means 'to remove part of the surface of the skin'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>excoriate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>exculpate</name>
	  <meaning>to prove (that someone is) not guilty</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After a high-profile criminal trial, O.J. Simpson was exculpated of the murder of his wife and her male companion.</example>
	  <etymology>1650s, from Medieval Latin exculpatus, past participle of exculpare, from Latin ex culpa, from ex "from" (see ex-) + culpa ablative of culpa "blame, fault." Related: Exculpated; exculpating.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>exculpate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>execrable</name>
	  <meaning>damnable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. President Mugabe has allowed inflation to escalate; as a consequence many Zimbabweans live in execrable poverty.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin exsecrati: to curse (the inverse of sacrare: to dedicate)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>execrable</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>exemplar</name>
	  <meaning>an outstanding example</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the UK, the Queen is a leading exemplar of selfless duty</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin exemplum: a sample, imitation</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>exemplar</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>exigent</name>
	  <meaning>demanding</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After performing, Pavarotti could barely speak because the physical demands of singing were so exigent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin exigere: to demand</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>exigent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>expatiate</name>
	  <meaning>(of speech) to elaborate</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. On the TV show Richard and Judy, Judy frequently looked at the camera while Richard expatiated.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin exspatiari: to move beyond one's usual bounds, from ex: out, spatiari: to walk</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>expatiate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>expedient</name>
	  <meaning>(of an action) convenient, although possibly morally wrong</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Critics of David Cameron say he pursues whichever policy is most politically expedient.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin expedire: to extricate, originally by freeing one's feet from being tied up (from ex: out, and pes, ped: foot)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>expedient</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>expiate</name>
	  <meaning>to make up for (a sin)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Catholics believe that, with prayer and compensatory acts, their sins can be expiated.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin expiat: appeased by sacrifice, from the verb expiare, from ex: out, and piare, from pious: pious.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>expiate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>expostulate</name>
	  <meaning>to express strong objections</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Clark Gable failed his early film auditions because the studios considered his ears too floppy, he would expostulate at length.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin expostulare: to demand</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>expostulate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>expurgate</name>
	  <meaning>to remove matter deemed improper (from a work)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Serial womaniser Casanova kept one fingernail especially long so that he could use it to expurgate the wax in his ears.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin expurgare: to thoroughly cleanse, from ex: out, and purgare: to cleanse</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>expurgate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>extemporise</name>
	  <meaning>(of music or a speech) to perform spontaneously</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Louis Armstrong, like every good jazz musician, was capable of extemporizing at will.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ex tempore: (arising) out of the time</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>extemporise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>extirpate</name>
	  <meaning>to rip out by the roots and destroy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Before his conversion, St Paul was a Roman official devoted to extirpating Christianity.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin exstirpare, from ex: out, and stirps: a stem</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>extirpate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>factious</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a state of conflict within an organisation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After losing the general election the Labour Party became factious; Gordon Brown then quickly resigned.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin facere: to do</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>factious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>factotum</name>
	  <meaning>an employee who performs many tasks</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his book A Royal Duty, Paul Burrell wrote about his experiences as factotum to Princess Diana.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin facere: to do, and totum: the whole thing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>factotum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fait accompli</name>
	  <meaning>a thing that has been settled before those affected hear about it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When one spouse decides to divorce the other, the decision is usually presented as a fait accompli.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French fait accompli: accomplished fact</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fait-accompli</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fallacy</name>
	  <meaning>an incorrect belief</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. There is no evidence that a monster lurks in Loch Ness - its supposed existence is a fallacy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fallacia: deceit</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fallacy</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fatuous</name>
	  <meaning>silly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Adults may find children's TV programme fatuous.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fatuus: foolish</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fatuous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>faux-naif</name>
	  <meaning>(of a work of art of a person) naive in an affected way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Agatha Christie's novels, detective Miss Marple lures murderers into a false sense of security with her faux-naif manner.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French faux: false, and naif: naive</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>faux-naif</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>febrile</name>
	  <meaning>excited in a nervy way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In 2008, Lehman Brothers went bust; this made stock markets febrile and share prices fluctuated violently.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin febris: fever; febrile literally means 'having the symptoms of a fever'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>febrile</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>feckless</name>
	  <meaning>irresponsible and not considering others</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A husband who walks out on his pregnant wife is feckless.</example>
	  <etymology>from the northern English dialect feck (from effeck, variant of 'effect').</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>feckless</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fecund</name>
	  <meaning>capable of producing many offspring</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. An hourglass figure is attractive to a man because it shows that a woman is fecund.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fecundus: fruitful</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fecund</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>felicity</name>
	  <meaning>a pleasing manner of expression; OR the state of being happy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barack Obama is famous for speaking with a felicity that no other politician can match.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin felicitas: happiness</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>felicity</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fetid</name>
	  <meaning>smelling very unsavoury</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When investigators opened the door to serial killer Ted Bundy's home; the fetid odour of decay assaulted them.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fetere: to stink</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fetid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fetishise</name>
	  <meaning>to develop an irrational devotion to (something)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The public fetishised the marriage between Princess Diana and Prince Charles because here beauty and his royalty made it a fairytale romance.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the Portuguese word feitico: a charm</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fetishise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>finagle</name>
	  <meaning>to obtain (something) by roguish means</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The media have suggested that Bernhard Madoff bought his large houses with money he had finagled from others.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French fornier: to deny</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>finagle</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fissile</name>
	  <meaning>able to split apart with ease</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It's hoped that any asteroid approaching Earth disintegrates before impact: but woe betide humanity if the asteroid is not fissile.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fiss: split (from the verb findere: to split, cleave)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fissile</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fissure</name>
	  <meaning>a state of discord</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The writer Dostoevsky gambled away so much money that his wife had to pawn her wedding ring, causing fissures in the marriage.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fissura: a cleft, from findere: to split, cleave; a fissure literally means 'a long narrow opening made by cracking'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fissure</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>flaneur</name>
	  <meaning>someone who lounges around</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Audrey Hepburn eventually abandoned films in favour of working for UNICEF because she had grown bored of being a flaneur.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French flaner: to lounge</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>flaneur</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>flaxen</name>
	  <meaning>(esp. of hair) of the light yellow colour of dressed flax (which is a type of fibre)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Grace Kelly was renowned for her flaxen locks.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English fleax: cloth made with linen.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>flaxen</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>flotilla</name>
	  <meaning>a group moving together</meaning>
	  <example>e.g.  An appearance on Oprah Winfrey's book club ensures an author sells millions more books because of the resulting flotilla of interested journalists.</example>
	  <etymology>With a navy, flotilla refers to a group of small warships of the same type, such as submarines or minesweepers. Today, flotilla is used most commonly to evoke the image of a small group of people moving around together.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>flotilla</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>flummery</name>
	  <meaning>hollow compliments</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Queen's speech is popular because people sense the Queen is speaking sincerely: it is far more than flummery coming out of her mouth.</example>
	  <etymology>flummery refers to a pudding consisting of stewed fruit thickened with cornflour. This pudding gained popularity in the 17th century when it was shaped by a mould and served to applause. However, its taste was bland and unimpressive. So it is that today we continue to use the word 'flummery' to refer to any applause that is meaningless or any praise that is hollow.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>flummery</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>folderol</name>
	  <meaning>silly fussing</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barack Obama's daughters looked amused by their father's presidential inauguration ceremony and the attendant folderol.</example>
	  <etymology>from a nonsense refrain of 'fol-de-rol' in songs from the 19th century.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>folderol</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>folie de grandeur</name>
	  <meaning>delusions of grandeur</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To judge by the number of statues of himself he had built, Saddam Hussein suffered from folie de grandeur.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French folie: madness, from de: of, and grandeur: grandeur</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>folie-de-grandeur</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>foment</name>
	  <meaning>to stir up (on unpleasant sentiment)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Billionaire recluse Howard Hughes forbade his staff from talking to him lest they expel germs in his direction; this ban fomented resentment towards him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin fomentum resentment towards him.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>foment</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fontanelle</name>
	  <meaning>a gap between the bones of the skull in an infant, where the bone has not yet grown over</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. You have to make sure when patting a young baby's head not to press down on the fontanella because it is a very delicate area.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French fontanelle, the diminutive of fontaine: spring; this soft spot of a baby's head was meant to resemble the dent in the earth where a spring rises.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fontanelle</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>force majeure</name>
	  <meaning>to declare that an event is beyond one's control</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As it was raining incessantly, the organisers of the cricket match called force majeure and cancelled the game.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French force majeure: greater force</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>force-majeure</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fountainhead</name>
	  <meaning>the source of something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Beatles remain a fountainhead of inspiration for many bands.</example>
	  <etymology>literally referring to a stream's source</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fountainhead</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>friable</name>
	  <meaning>easily reduced to powder by the act of crumbling</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. You must be careful when arranging dried flowers because they are friable.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin friare: to crumble.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>friable</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>frond</name>
	  <meaning>a mass formed by strands of hair</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Marilyn Monroe is famous for her blonde hair which tumbled from the head in fronds.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin frans, frondis: a leaf; a frond literally means 'the leaf of a palm, fern, or similar plant'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>frond</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>fulminate against</name>
	  <meaning>to express violent protest about something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When a wife fulminates against her husband, he will often fight back.</example>
	  <etymology>fulminate derives from the Latin word for lightning (fulmen, fulmunis) and means 'to protest violently'; this is because, in Greek mythology, when the god Zeus became angry, he would hurl a thunderbolt at the person who had irked him. The verb fulminate has the following extra meanings: - (of lightning) to flash (in a literal sense - rather than in the metaphorical sense above) - (of a disease) to flare up    e.g. The doctor operated on the patient at once to cut out the fulminating appendix.
	  </etymology>
	  <pronunciation>fulminate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gallimaufry</name>
	  <meaning>a messy jumble</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Most high streets are composed of a gallimaufry of shops and restaurants.</example>
	  <etymology>from the archaic French galimafree: ragout</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>gallimaufry</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>garrulous</name>
	  <meaning>too talkative, especially on matters that are unimportant</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Einstein's parents at first thought he was retarded because he said nothing until the age of five; but Einstein grew into a garrulous adult.</example>
	  <etymology>1610s, from Latin garrulus "talkative," from garrire "to chatter," from PIE root *gar- "to call, cry," of imitative origin (cf. Greek gerys "voice, sound," Ossetic zar "song," Welsh garm, Old Irish gairm "noise, cry"). Related: Garrulously; garrulousness.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>garrulous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gerrymander</name>
	  <meaning>to redefine an electoral constituency so as to favour one party</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. in the UK, politically neutral organisations define the boundaries of electoral constituencies so as to eliminate the risk of gerrymandering.</example>
	  <etymology>The verb gerrymander originated in the early 19th century, arising from the combination of the name of one Governor Elbridge Gerry of Massachusetts with the word 'salamander'. Seeing that his political party was about to lose an election, Governor Gerry signed a new bill into law that redrew the electoral boundaries to favour his party. This new area happened to include one district that was shaped like a salamander, a creature that looks like a newt. A journalist noted this resemblance and soon there appeared in The Boston Weekly Messenger a drawing of a salamander - but with claws and wings added to enhance the impression of evil at work - that was given the title The Gerry-mander (to evoke the name of the meddlesome Governor Gerry). Today we continue to use the word gerrymander to describe any attempt by a political party to draw up new voting districts to swing the vote its way.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>gerrymander</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ghoulish</name>
	  <meaning>referring to a person obsessed with death and tragedy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The sudden death of someone as well known as Diana Princess of Wales is of interest to everyone, not just to the ghoulish.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Arabic gul: a desert demon believed to rob graves and devour corpses.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ghoulish</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gimcrack</name>
	  <meaning>badly made but attractive in a deceptive way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When on holiday people are often tempted to buy gimcrack gifts - such as engraved seashells - which they regret purchasing when they get home.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Middle English gibecrake: a kind of ornament</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>gimcrack</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gimlet-eyed</name>
	  <meaning>having eyes with a penetrating stare</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. One reason for Daniel Craig being chosen to play James Bond was his gimlet-eyed gaze.</example>
	  <etymology>from the English word, gimlet: a tool for boring holes; gimlet-eyed literally means 'having eyes like a gimlet'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>glacial</name>
	  <meaning>very slow (like the movement of a glacier, which is a mass of slow-moving ice formed from compacted snow on mountains)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Funeral hearses move at a glacial speed compared to normal traffic.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin glacialis: icy. It also has the following extra meaning: - very cold</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>glacial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>glib</name>
	  <meaning>talking fluently but without sincerity</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jeeves creator P. G. Woodhouse used to live exclusively in ground floor flats so that he could avoid small talk with glib elevator operators.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Dutch, glibberig: slippery</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>glib</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gloaming</name>
	  <meaning>the time between daylight and darkness</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The number of road accidents increases during the gloaming because many drivers haven't yet turned their lights on.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English glomung, from glom: twilight. gloaming is the early onset of twilight (the time immediately after sunset when the light is faint; dusk is the later, darker stage of twilight).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>gloaming</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>gnomic</name>
	  <meaning>(of an utterance) enigmatic and pithy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. 'My wallpaper and I are fighting a duel to the death. One or other of us has to go,' was Oscar Wilde's gnomic deathbed utterance.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek gnomai: sayings, maxims.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>gnomic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Grand Guignol</name>
	  <meaning>drama that entertains but is horrific</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The most famous example of Grand Guignol in recent times is the film Sweeney Todd starring Johnny Depp.</example>
	  <etymology>The English term Grand Guignol originates from the name of the French theatre Le Theatre du Grand-Guignol (The theatre of the Big Puppet), which was formed in Paris in 1897. This theatre was a place of gore, staging horror shows; the success of each performance was gauged by the number of people who fainted. After the all too real horrors of World War II, demand for artificial horror subsided and the theatre closed. However, we still use the word today to refer to any play or film which uses gory special effects to shock.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>grass roots</name>
	  <meaning>ordinary people rather than those at the centre of major political activity</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Oliver Cromwell abolished Christmas in the 17th century and turned it into an ordinary working day, he should have predicted that the grass roots of his party would object to this.</example>
	  <etymology>The term grass roots was first used by a certain Senator Beveridge of Indiana, who said in 1912 of the Progressive Party that had just been formed. 'This party has come from the "grass roots". It has grown from the soil of people's hard necessities. Today, we continue to use the phrase grass roots to refer to any political movement that has arisen as a result of discontent amongst ordinary voters - rather than as a result of politician's machinations.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hagiography</name>
	  <meaning>a biography that idealises the person described, as if they were a saint</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The book with the title The Rise of Boris Johnson suggests a hagiography of the politician but in fact offers a balanced view of the subject.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek hagios: holy, and graphe: writing; hagiography literally means 'the writing of the lives of the saints'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hagiography</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>halycon</name>
	  <meaning>denoting a happy and peaceful time in the past</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Most people look back on their childhood as consisting of halycon days.</example>
	  <etymology>In Greek mythology, the halycon (halykon in Greek) was a type of kingfisher that built its nest by the sea. To explain how any bird could bring up its young by a noisy and raging sea, the Greeks attributed to this kingfisher the power to render the wind and the waves calm. So it is that today, when we refer to halycon days, we evoke a period of calm.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>halcyon</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>harmatia</name>
	  <meaning>a flaw that brings about the destruction of a hero</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Marilyn Monroe's harmatia was a fondness for men in power: many say this lead to her death.</example>
	  <etymology>The term harmatia was first used by the ancient Greeks to describe an error in judgement.   Nowadays, harmatia is used to mean something slightly different: a character's 'tragic flaw' that ultimately destroys him. A good example occurs in one of the most famous novels of the 20th century: The Great Gatsby (1925). Jay Gatsby's harmatia is his unreciprecated love for a married lady called Daisy; when Daisy runs over and kills a woman by accident, Gatsby claims it is he who was responsible and, as a result, is murdered by the victim's husband.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hamartia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>harbinger</name>
	  <meaning>something that heralds the approach of another</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a child, Oprah Winfrey played games interviewing the crows in her garden: this was the harbinger of her success as a chat show host.</example>
	  <etymology>The word harbinger derives from the French word herberger, which means 'someone who provides lodging' (itself originating from herberge, meaning 'lodging'). Later the woord came to mean 'a man who went ahead to find lodgings for an army' - hence 'a forerunner', and this sense persists today.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>harbinger</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>harpy</name>
	  <meaning>a woman known for her grasping nature</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If an attractive young woman marries a rich old man, society is quick to label the woman a harpy.</example>
	  <etymology>A harpy was in Greek mythology a flying creature with a woman's head but a monster's body. Harpies would descend from the sky and snatch food from the hands of humans on the ground: It is for this reason that the literal meaning of harpy (harpazein - to snatch in Greek) is 'someone who snatches'. Today we continue to refer to any grasping woman as a harpy.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>harpy</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hawkish</name>
	  <meaning>advocating war or aggression</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Towards the end of his life, Elvis Presley amassed an arsenal of weapons - including 32 handguns - because chronic drug abuse had made him hawkish.</example>
	  <etymology>hawkish derives from 'hawk', a warlike bird; the direct opposite is dovish.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hawkish</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>heft</name>
	  <meaning>the amount of power that one wields</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. George Bush's detractors depicted him as lacking the intellectual heft for the Presidency.</example>
	  <etymology>heft derives from 'heft', the obsolete past participle of the verb 'heave'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>heft</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hegemony</name>
	  <meaning>leadership</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With three successive league championships between 2007 and 2009, Manchester united's hegemony within English football is clear.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek hegemon: leader</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hegemony</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>heterogeneous</name>
	  <meaning>made up of diverse units</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Aside from a love of tennis, it is hard to find commonality among the crowds at the Wimbledon tennis championships: they form a heterogeneous group.</example>
	  <etymology>The direct opposite of heterogeneous is homogeneous, meaning 'made up of units that exactly the same as each other'. For example, penguins are pretty much indistinguishable to humans; in other words, as far as we are concerned, these birds form a homogeneous mass.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>heterogeneous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hew to</name>
	  <meaning>to stick to</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Steven Spielberg's films - Jaws, for example - all hew to his action-packed vision of story-telling.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the 19th-century phrase 'to hew to the line', meaning 'to cut evenly with a saw'; this reconciles the German root, hauen: 'to cut' with the seemingly contradictory English expression 'to hew to', meaning 'to stick to'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hew</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hidebound</name>
	  <meaning>unwilling to adapt due to one's upbringing</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In Romeo and Juliet, both sets of parents cannot accept the union of their progeny because they are hidebound by historical feuds with one another.</example>
	  <etymology>hidebound was first used in the 16th century to describe cattle that had been undernourished, which led to their skin clinging closely to their back and ribs (and in this sense, their innards were bound together by their hides alone). hidebound then evolved in meaning to refer to undernourished human beings, before assuming today's usage - which is 'undernourished in outlook' and thus 'unwilling to change'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hidebound</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>highfalutin</name>
	  <meaning>(of language) grand-sounding</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Novels are divided into those that are commercial, such as The Divinci Code - and those that are considered highfalutin, such as Proust's works.</example>
	  <etymology>highfalutin derives from the words 'high' and 'fluting': together, these words mean 'to speak in a melodious way reminiscent of the sound of a flute'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>highfalutin</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hinterland</name>
	  <meaning>a realm beyond the things that are known (about someone or something)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the two bestsellers he wrote before he became President, Barack Obama discusses his religious beliefs and other areas of the hinterland.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German, hinter: behind, and land: land; hinterland literally refers to the uncharted areas beyond a river's banks.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hinterland</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hortatory</name>
	  <meaning>vigorously encouraging</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. While conducting, Tchaikovsky held onto his chin with one hand: he had a phobia that his head would roll off otherwise due to his hortatory hand movements.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin hortari: to exhort</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hortatory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hubris</name>
	  <meaning>excessive pride</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bernard Madoff showed hubris in believing he could deceive so many investors forever; nemesis came when his fraud was discovered and he was imprisoned for life.</example>
	  <etymology>hubris was the term given by the Greeks to describe the behaviour of anyone whose excessive pride led him or her to challenge the gods. Excessive pride is traditionally punished by the equal and opposite force of retributive justice; the Greeks called this power nemesis; the contemporary expression 'pride comes before a fall' also describes this relationship. So, such a display of hubris by Bernard Madoff - who thought he could fool all of the people all of the time - was always going to be punished by nemesis.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hubris</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>husband</name>
	  <meaning>(or resources) to use sparingly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Oprah Winfrey was born to a single teenage mother who had to husband the few resources she had.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old Norse hus: a house</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>husband</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Hydra</name>
	  <meaning>a problem that is hard to conquer because it will not go away</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Trying to stop the spread of AIDS in Africa is like trying to kill the Hydra; there may be short-lived successes but, sadly, the problem seems perennial.</example>
	  <etymology>The Lernaean Hydra was in Greek mythology a sea monster with many heads who guarded an underwater entrance to the Underworld. If one of its heads was chopped off, two would grow back in its place; but there was hope for anyone seeking to vanquish the Hydra in combat as only one of its heads was immortal. As one of his 12 labours, Hercules had to defeat the Hydra. He did this by chopping off each head, then by having his nephew cauterise each stump to prevent regrowth. Hercules then pushed a huge rock on top of the immortal head. Today, we continue to refer to a problem that seems impossible to overcome as a Hydra.
	  </etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hydra</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>hyperbole</name>
	  <meaning>deliberate exaggeration for effect</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When people exclaim 'over my dead body!', they are not talking about literally dying for a cause but are using hyperbole to make a point.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek huperbole: excess, from huper: above, and ballein: to throw</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>hyperbole</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>idee fixe</name>
	  <meaning>an idea that has become an obsession</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Imelda Marcos accumulated as many pairs of shoes as possible: amassing footwear was an idee fixe for her.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French idee fixe: fixed idea</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>idee-fixe</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ideologue</name>
	  <meaning>a dogmatic follower of an ideology</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Iran's status as a fundamentalist Islamic republic was cemented by the ideologue Ayatollah Khomeini (1900-1989).</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek idea: form, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ideologue</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>idiosyncratic</name>
	  <meaning>(of a characteristic) peculiar to an individual</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jimmy Connor's double-handed backhand was a key part of his idiosyncratic style on the tennis court.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek idios: private, and sunkratos: mixed together.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>idiosyncratic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>imbroglio</name>
	  <meaning>a very messy and embarrassing situation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When his wife's younger sister died, Charles Dickens took the ring off the dead woman's finger and wore it until he died: this caused quite an imbroglio.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian, imbrogliare: to confuse</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>imbroglio</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>immanent</name>
	  <meaning>existing in</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. While we are all aware that death is immanent in life, we still find it hard to accept the thought of our own mortality.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin in: in, and manere: to remain</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>immanent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>impassible</name>
	  <meaning>incapable of feeling hardship</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Indian fakirs who walk barefoot across hot coals give the impression of being impassible.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin in: not, and pass: suffered (from the verb, pati)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>impassible</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>impecunious</name>
	  <meaning>poor</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Audrey Hepburn's grave is a small mound marked by a simple cross - to look at it, you might assume the actress was impecunious.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin im: not, and pecunia: money; impecunious literally means 'having no money'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>impecunious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>impervious</name>
	  <meaning>not affected by</meaning>
	  <example>e.g From the age of eight, Mark Twain smoked on average 30 cigars a day until he died: he was impervious to doctor's advice to quit.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>impervious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>imprimatur</name>
	  <meaning>a person's guarantee that something is of good quality</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Kim Jong-il's youngest son, Kim Jong-un, is expected to assume control of North Korea on his father's death because he enjoys his father's imprimatur.</example>
	  <etymology>imprimatur means in Latin, 'let it be printed'. Imprimatur at first described an official declaration by the Roman Catholic Church that a book contained no errors in matters of Catholic doctrine - and so could be read by the faithful. The word imprimatur today has a wider meaning, referring to a guarantee by anyone that something is up to scratch.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>imprimatur</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>incandescent</name>
	  <meaning>burning with anger; OR of blindingly good quality</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Isaac Newton was so absent-minded he once used his fiancée's finger to push down the tobacco in his pipe: this made her incandescent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin incandescere: to glow; incandescent literally means 'emitting light as a result of being heated'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>incandescent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>incendiary</name>
	  <meaning>tending to stir up trouble</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jeremy Paxman has made his incendiary comments about the deteriorating quality of Marks and  Spencer's Y-fronts.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin incendere: to set fire to; incendiary literally means 'causing fires'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>incendiary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>inchoate</name>
	  <meaning>just started and thus not in a final state</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Monika Lewinsky must wonder what might have been had Bill Clinton not called off their affair when it was still inchoate.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin incohare: to begin</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>inchoate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>incongruous</name>
	  <meaning>not in harmony with the other elements of something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Charlie Chaplin was 54, he married an 18-year-old girl; this age difference made the couple look incongruous</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin incongruus, from in: not, and congruus: agreeing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>incongruous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>indentured</name>
	  <meaning>(of a labourer) bound by a formal agreement</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some women form such close bonds with their mothers that they seem indentured to them.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin in: into, and dens, dent: a tooth; in indenture originally referred to a document that was indented; then to a sealed agreement binding an apprentice to his master.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>indentured</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>indigent</name>
	  <meaning>impoverished</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a noted philanthropist, billionaire stock market trader George Soros donates money to the indigent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin indigere: to need</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>indigent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ineffable</name>
	  <meaning>(of a sentiment) too great to be uttered in words</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When the attend church, religious people speak of experiencing ineffable joy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ineffabilis. From in: not, and effabilis, from effari: to utter.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ineffable</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ineluctable</name>
	  <meaning>inescapable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After Lehman Brothers collapsed, a worldwide financial crisis became ineluctable.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin in: not, and eluctari: to struggle out.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ineluctable</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>in extremis</name>
	  <meaning>in a very troublesome situation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When the sailors were 50 miles from shore, a storm suddenly arose and they found themselves in extermis.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin in extermis: in the outermost parts.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>in-extremis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>infelicity</name>
	  <meaning>an unpleasing manner of expression; OR unhappiness</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The speech of young children who are still learning how to talk is littered with infelicities.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin infelix: unhappy</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>infelicity</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>infraction</name>
	  <meaning>a breaking of a rule</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If any player other than the goalkeeper uses his hands on a football pitch, he is guilty of an infraction of the rules.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin infractio: a breaking, from infringere, from in: into, and frangere: to break.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>infraction</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>inquisitorial</name>
	  <meaning>so prying as to be insulting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many people associate the concept of psychotherapy with lying on a couch whilst an inquisitorial individual asks about your childhood.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin inquirere: to inquire; inquisitorial literally means '(of a trial) in which the judge has a role as inquirer'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>inquisitorial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>insignia</name>
	  <meaning>a mark that characterises something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Instead of buying a ring, the film producer Matthew Vaugn presented Claudia Schiffer with a tortoise as an insignia of their engagement.</example>
	  <etymology>1640s, from Latin insignia, neuter plural of insigne "badge, mark," from in- "in" (see in- (2)) + signum "mark" (see sign). Singular is insigne.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>insignia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>insouciance</name>
	  <meaning>an attitude devoid of worry</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Princess Grace's fatal car crash was on a road she knew well from filming To Catch a Thief: no it was not insouciance that killed the actress but a stroke.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French insouciant: not caring, from in: not, and sociant: worrying.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>insouciance</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>insurrection</name>
	  <meaning>the act of rising up against an authority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Actor Toby Stephens has joked he will never play James Bond because casting a Bond 'with reddish hair would cause insurrection'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin insurrectio, from insurgere: to rise up.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>insurrection</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>internecine</name>
	  <meaning>relating to strife within a group of people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The novelist Marcel Proust enjoyed placing starving rats in the same cage; when they tore each other to pieces, he would become sexually excited by this internecine display.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin inter: among, and necare: to kill</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>internecine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>interregnum</name>
	  <meaning>the period falling between reigns by two different rulers</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The gap between the Queen's death and the coronation of her successor will form an interregnum.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin inter: between, and regnum: reign</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>interregnum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>invective</name>
	  <meaning>abusive language</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Tired of his wife's invective, War and Peace author Leo Tolstoy left her a note stating his wish to spend his 'last days alone and in silence'. He died soon after.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin invectivuus: abusive, from invectus, past participle of invehere: to attack with words.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>invective</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>inveigh against</name>
	  <meaning>to verbally attack (something)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Knowing that the public blames capitalists for the credit crunch, politicians frequently inveigh against bankers.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin invehi: to attack with words</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>inveigh</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>invidious</name>
	  <meaning>(of a comparison) discriminating between people in an unfair fashion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A mother will rarely say which of her sons is her favourite because she knows no happiness can come from such an invidious comment.</example>
	  <etymology>c.1600, from Latin invidiosus "full of envy, envious," from invidia "envy, grudge, jealousy, ill will" (see envy). Related: Invidiously; invidiousness.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>invidious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>inviolable</name>
	  <meaning>never to be destroyed</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Catholic Church does not allow divorces to marry again, viewing marriage vows as inviolable.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin inviolabolis: invulnerable, from in: not, and violare: to do violence to</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>inviolable</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>irascible</name>
	  <meaning>(or a person) growing angry easily</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Composer Brahms used to shoot cats with a bow and arrow: he hated them so much that the mere sight of a feline made him irascible</example>
	  <etymology>late 14c., from Middle French irascible (12c.) and directly from Late Latin irascibilis, from Latin irasci "be angry, be in a rage," from ira "anger" (see ire).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>irascible</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>jejune</name>
	  <meaning>too simple; OR dull</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Whereas the views of most teenagers are jejune, the narrator of The Catcher in the Rye delivers mature insights that expose the hypocrisies of adults.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin jejunus: fasting; this sense of 'being physically undernourished' (as a result of fasting) evolved to mean 'being intellectually undernourished'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>jejune</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>jeremiad</name>
	  <meaning>a long moan</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Lord Byron was so fat he used to play cricket wearing a total of seven waistcoats in a bid to lose weight; when this failed, he embarked on a jerimiad.</example>
	  <etymology>jeremiad derives from the name of Jeremiah, who features in the Bible. Jeremiah was notorious for moaning - mainly about the destruction of Jerusalem (as described in The Lamentations of Jeremiah in the Old Testament). Today, when we use the word jeremiad, we conjure up the image of one long complaint.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>jeremiad</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>journeyman</name>
	  <meaning>a worker or sportsman who is reliable but not the best</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Roger Federer is famous but few people know the names of the lower-ranked journeymen of the tennis world.</example>
	  <etymology>In Middle English, 'a journey' used to mean 'a day's work' and a journeyman therefore referred to a worker who was paid for each day he worked - but whom the employer did not consider good enough to give a full-time contract to. When we use the word journeyman today, we evoke this pejorative sense of someone who is an 'also-ran'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>journeyman</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>juju</name>
	  <meaning>a lucky charm</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. James Joyce was a superstitious man who used to carry around rabbit's ears and other jujus to bring himself luck.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French joujou: toy</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>juju</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>juvenilia</name>
	  <meaning>works produced by an artist in his youth</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Imagine the excitement if somebody discovered the unread juvenilia of Shakespeare</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin juvenis: a young person</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>juvenilia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Kafkaesque</name>
	  <meaning>(of a situation) marked by menace and complexity</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Britons who are put on trial abroad often find the process Kafkaesque compared to the relatively straightforward British legal system.</example>
	  <etymology>Kafkaesque refers to those unpleasant situations and ideas that are suggestive of the books of Czech novelist Franz Kafka (1883-1924). Kafka's most famous novel, The Trial, tells the story of a man arrested and prosecuted by an enigmatic authority; but he never finds out what he has done wrong. The term 'Kafkaesque' is today applied to any situation where an individual is accused of a crime but where little - if any - evidence is offered to substantiate the accusation.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>kafkaesque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ken</name>
	  <meaning>the range of what one knows</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ivan the Terrible (1530-1584) used to sew victims into bearskins, then hunt them down with hounds; such cruelty is beyond most people's ken.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German kennen: to know</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ken</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lackadaisical</name>
	  <meaning>lacking in keenness</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. John Wayne made acting look natural because he appeared lackadaisical on screen.</example>
	  <etymology>from the archaic interjection 'lack-a-day' of a listless person which was used to convey disapproval; a phrase.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lackadaisical</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>laconic</name>
	  <meaning>uttering few words</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Boxer Mike Tyson never gave much away in post-fight interviews: he is a laconic man.</example>
	  <etymology>laconic originates from a place in Greece called 'Laconia' (to which the Greeks give the adjective Lakonikos). The inhabitants of Laconia (which was also known as Sparta) were notorious for not saying much; hence, when we call someone laconic today, we evoke this sense of terseness.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>laconic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lacuna</name>
	  <meaning>a gap that has not been filled</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After she read of a friend's death, Florence Nightingale was so affected by the resulting lacuna in her life that she cancelled her daily newspaper lest she read of any other such deaths.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lacuna</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lambent</name>
	  <meaning>(of light) flickering softly; (of humour) brilliant but with a light touch</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. 'I told you I was ill' were the words chosen by Spike Milligan for his epitaph: it was typical of him to treat his own death with such a lambent wit.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin lambent: licking, from lambere: to lick</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lambent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lampoon</name>
	  <meaning>to hold up to public ridicule</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. For years, the magazine Private Eye has lampooned celebrities.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French lampoon: originally meaning 'a drinking song', later 'a lampoon', deriving from lampons: let us drink, a refrain of 17th-century songs.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lampoon</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lapidary</name>
	  <meaning>(or language) so elegant that it is worth engraving on stone</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ernest Hemingway's dislike of adjectives means his sentences are concise and lapidary.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin lapis, lapidis: a stone</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lapidary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lard with</name>
	  <meaning>to enliven (sentences) with a variety of expressions</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ex-French President Mitterrand was fond of larding his speeches with quotations from Balzac and other French writers of old.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek larinos: fat; lard with literally means 'to smear a foodstuff with lard to prevent it from dying out during storage'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lard</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>leaven</name>
	  <meaning>to change (something) for the better</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The director Quentin Tarantino uses humorous dialogue to leaven the violence in his films.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin levare: to lift</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>leaven</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>legerdemain</name>
	  <meaning>sleight of hand</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. for years Oscar Wilde exercised considerable legerdemain in concealing his homosexuality from the public; but eventually he was outed and jailed.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French leger de main: light of hand; legerdemain literally means 'skilful use of one's hand when performing conjuring tricks'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>legerdemain</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>leonine</name>
	  <meaning>like a lion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bjorn Borg has maintained his long yellow hair into his middle age and with it his leonine look.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin lea, leonis: a lion</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>leonine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lese-majesty</name>
	  <meaning>an attack on authority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The French revolution (1789-1799), and the use of the guillotine that accompanied it, was the ultimate act of lese-majesty.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin laesa majestas: injured sovereignty; lese-majesty literally means 'the insulting of a ruler'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lese-majesty</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>leviathan</name>
	  <meaning>something very large, especially a large sea creature</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Billionaires often buy themselves large yachts and then hold parties on these leviathans.</example>
	  <etymology>leviathan is used in the Bible to refer to various monsters, such as the whale and the crocodile (in Job) and to the ultimate monster, the Devil (in Isaiah). Today, it continues to evoke any dangerous aquatic creature - often a whale but not always - or any large organisation or object (not necessarily a sea creature).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>leviathan</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>libertine</name>
	  <meaning>a person, especially a man, who disregards all moral codes, particularly in sexual matters</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the film Dangerous Liaisons, John Malkovich plays the ultimate libertine: an aristocrat who sexually corrupts the innocent.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin libertinus: freedman, from liber: free</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>libertine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>licentious</name>
	  <meaning>unbridled in sexual matters</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. James Bond beds several women in each film, reflecting his licentious approach to relationships.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin licentia: freedom</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>licentious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Lilliputian</name>
	  <meaning>very small in size; OR trivial</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Paris may be the capital city of France, but it seems Lilliputian when compared to the sprawling metropolis that is London.</example>
	  <etymology>The Lilliputians were people around six inches tall who inhabited the fictional island of Lilliput in Jonathan Swift's novel Gulliver's Travels (1726). In the novel, Gulliver is washed up on the island of Lilliput, and implored by the tiny Lilliputians to fight the people on a neighbouring island. The island of Lilliput was used by Swift to parody England at the time. For example, Swift talks about a conflict in Lilliput between those people who prefer to open an egg from its big end and those people who opt for the small end; this is a reference to the ongoing arguments in England between the Catholics (the 'Big-Endians') and the Protestants (the 'Little-Endians'). Today, we use the word Lilliputian to denote something that is physically tiny or a matter that is very trivial.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lilliputian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>liminal</name>
	  <meaning>in a transitional state</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As he waited for the defeated President Bush to see out his final days in office, President-elect Barack Obama found himself in a liminal state.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin limen, liminis: a threshold; liminal literally means 'standing on both sides of a threshold'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>liminal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>limpid</name>
	  <meaning>(of liquid or of writing) crystal clear</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Brigitte Bardot was an iconic sex symbol of the 1960s, renowned for her limpid blue eyes.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin limpidus: clear</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>limpid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lingua franca</name>
	  <meaning>a language that is taken on as a common language between speakers whose mother tongues are different</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. English people on holiday in France use 'franglais' to communicate with the locals: basic exchanges can be effected using this lingua franca.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian, lingua franca: Frankish tongue</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lingua-franca</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>litotes</name>
	  <meaning>ironic understatement in which a sentiment is expressed by negating its contrary proposition</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. I deduced from the English teacher's use of the litotes: 'I am not unfamiliar with the works of Dickens', that he was an expert on the novelist.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek liotes, from litos: plain, meagre</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>litotes</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lodestar</name>
	  <meaning>a person or thing that serves as a guiding force</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barack Obama cites Martin Luther King so often that it is clear King is a lodestar for him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Middle English lodesterre, from lode: way, and steree: star; lodestar literally means 'a star that is used to guide the course of a ship'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lodestar</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>logorrheic</name>
	  <meaning>uncontrollably talkative</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Freud said of the Irish: "This is one race of people whom psychoanalysis is of no use whatsoever." Presumably because the Irish are so logorrheic that it is hard to know which bits coming out of their mouths are important.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>logorrheic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>lore</name>
	  <meaning>a body of knowledge on a topic, that has typically been passed from person to person via the oral tradition</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When writing the Bond novel Devil May Care, Sebastian Faulks consulted Ian Fleming's family on matters of Bond lore.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English lar: instruction, of Germanic origin, related to the German Lehre: learning.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>lore</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Luddite</name>
	  <meaning>a person who is against new technology</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some people over the age of 70 are Luddites who do not know how to suurf the Internet.</example>
	  <etymology>Luddite derives from the name of Ned Lud, a member of a 19th-century group of English cotton mill workers who destroyed machinery that was threatening to take over their jobs. Today, when we call someone a Luddite, we are referring to someone who opposes new technology of any kind.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>luddite</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ludic</name>
	  <meaning>playful</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Playwright Arthur Miller praised his ex-wife Marilyn Monroe for her sense of fun, and noted that most adults lacked this ludic quality.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ludere: to play</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ludic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Machiavellian</name>
	  <meaning>wily and unscrupulous in furthering one's own career</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The public regards politicians as Machiavellian types</example>
	  <etymology>Machiavellian originates from the name of Machiavelli, a Renaissance Italian statesman.   Machiavelli's book The Prince (1532) advises rulers that unethical methods are necessary if power is to be seized and effectively wielded. Today, we continue to describe someone as Machiavellian if they stab rivals in the back, or mistreat people in other ways in the pursuit of power.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>machiavellian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>magisterial</name>
	  <meaning>authoritative</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Steven Spielberg's self-confidence means he exudes a magisterial air on set.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin magister: master</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>magisterial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>malapropism</name>
	  <meaning>mistakenly using one word in the place of another (often with an unintentionally comic effect)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. I decided to tell my friends about my flamenco dancing lessons but it came out wrong and I ended up saying: 'I can dance a flamingo now', they laughed at my malapropism.</example>
	  <etymology>malapropism derives from the name of the character Mrs Malaprop in Richard Sheridan's play The Rivals (1775). Mys Malaprop has the habit of getting words confused, which is a source of humour in the play. Her name was chosen because of the link to the French phrase mal a propos, which means 'ill-suited' and describes perfectly the jumbled order of her words. Today, when we say that someone has committed a malapropism, we mean they are guilty of a similar linguistic slip-up.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>malapropism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>malfeasance</name>
	  <meaning>malpractice, especially by a public official</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The MP's expenses' scandal revealed that politicians had been using tyaqxpayers' money to pay a variety of items for personal use: this malfeasance caused a public outcry.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French mal: evil, and faisance: activity</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>malfeasance</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>malinger</name>
	  <meaning>to pretend to be ill to avoid work</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Every year the government loses millions of pounds owing to workers pretending to be sick; as taxpayers, we are all victims of this malingering.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French mal: wrongly, and haingre: weak</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>malinger</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mandarin</name>
	  <meaning>a powerful government worker</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the UK, the head of MI6 is one of the most powerful mandarins</example>
	  <etymology>ultimately deriving from the Sanskrit mantri: a counsellor; a mandarin literally refers to a bureaucrat in imperial Chine (AD 900-1800).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mandarin</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Manichaean</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a view that divides the world very starkly into good and evil</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. George Bush spoke about certain countries forming an 'axis of evil': this implies he sees the world in Manichaean terms, with the USA being 'good', and these other mentioned countries as being 'evil'.</example>
	  <etymology>Manichaean derives from 'Manichaeism', a 3rd-century religion that was one of the most popular in the world at the time. This religion was based on the teachings of the Iranian prophet Mani who was privy to divine truths from a spirit who visited him. Manichaeism is distinguished by its viewing the world as a clear-cut struggle between good (or 'spiritually'); and evil (or 'materialism'); today, when we call someone Manichaean, we mean they see the world as being divided very clearly between good and evil.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>manichaean</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>manque</name>
	  <meaning>referring to someone who missed out on a particular role</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. US senator Ted Kennedy never achieved his political potential because allegations of drinking and womanising dogged him throughout his life: he was the President manque</example>
	  <etymology>from the French manquer: to miss</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>manque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>marionette</name>
	  <meaning>a puppet controlled from above by strings attached to it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The SS was a major Nazi organisation composed of one million of Hitler's marionettes</example>
	  <etymology>from the French marionette: little Mary, the diminutive form of Marion, which is itself the diminutive of Marie</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>marionette</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>marmoreal</name>
	  <meaning>like marble</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To those who found actress Grace Kelly marmoreal, Alfred Hitchcock said of his leading lady that she had 'fire under the ice'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin marmor: marble</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>marmoreal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>martinet</name>
	  <meaning>a strict taskmaster</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. 'Fat farms' are populated by obese people who are whipped into shape by martinets.</example>
	  <etymology>martinet derives from the name of the 17th-century Frenchman Jean Martinet, a highly-ordered man who trained soldiers.  Tired of having to deal with fickle mercenaries, Martinet devised a rigorous programme to turn members of the public into effective military servicemen. It is a cruel irony that this paragon of discipline was killed by 'friendly fire': a fatal form of ill-discipline. Today, the word martinet refers to any disciplinarian.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>martinet</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>maunder on</name>
	  <meaning>to talk in a meandering fashion; OR to move or act as if time is of no concern</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his satirical sketches of political figures, Rory Bremner contorts his face to better depict his victims as he maunders on in their tone of voice.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English maund: to beg, deriving from the French mendier: to beg.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>maunder</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>maw</name>
	  <meaning>the throat of a ravenous animal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Hound of the Baskervilles is a story about a giant dog suspected of killing people using its fearsome maw.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German Magen: stomach</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>maw</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mawkish</name>
	  <meaning>sentimental in a nausea-inducing way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The final scene of a 'rom com' typically involves a girl running into the arms of a boy or some other equally mawkish scene.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English mawke: maggot; mawkish originally meant 'to be disgusted', as if by a putrid meat.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mawkish</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mellifluous</name>
	  <meaning>(of a voice) honey-coated</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The advent of sound meant Clark Gable's career took off overnight because there was suddenly huge demand for his mellifluous voice.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin mellifluus, from mel: honey, and fluere: to flow</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mellifluous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>menagerie</name>
	  <meaning>a diverse mixture of people or animals</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Each year the cast of Celebrity Big Brother is made up of a variety of people in the public eye, such as TV stars and glamour models: a veritable menagerie of individuals.</example>
	  <etymology>A menagerie was a 16th-century French term used to describe a collection of exotic animals kept in captivity; the French word menagerie is derived from the word menage, meaning 'a household'. A menagerie was often retained by a royal court, no so much as to study the animal world but rather to signify the opulence of the menagerie's owner (as exotic animals were very expensive to purchase). Today, menagerie refers to any diverse collection of things or people.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>menagerie</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mercurial</name>
	  <meaning>very moody</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Idi Amin (1925-2003), the despotic ruler of Uganda for many years, was a mercurial man who had people executed on a whim.
	  </example>
	  <etymology>mercurial derives from the Latin word mercurialis, which meant 'relating to the god Mercury'.   The god Mercury would fly quickly from one place to another and back again - it is this erraticism (albeit of a mental, rather than a physical, kind) that we evoke when we call someone mercurial today.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mercurial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>meretricious</name>
	  <meaning>alluring but vulgar</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A woman who obviously had breast augmentation surgery holds a meretricious appeal for some men.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin meretrix, meretricis: a prostitute; meretricious literally means 'like a prostitute'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>meretricious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>metonym</name>
	  <meaning>a word used instead of another word with which it is closely linked</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Newspapers are produced using a printing press; hence the term 'the press' has become a metonym to describe all newspapers collectively.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek metanomasia: change of name</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>metonym</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>miasma</name>
	  <meaning>an atmosphere that has been polluted</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. during the Second World War, Jews in Germany lived their lives in a miasma of fear and suspicion.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek miama: a stain (especially due to a murder)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>miasma</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>microcosm</name>
	  <meaning>a situation that reflects on a smaller scale the qualities of a larger situation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some saw England's defeat of Germany in the 1966 Football World Cup as a microcosm of England's defeat of Germany in World War II.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>microcosm</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mimesis</name>
	  <meaning>the rendering of the real world in art</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Shakespeare's play Henry V is a mimesis of Britain's victory over the French at Agincourt.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek mimeistai: to imitate</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mimesis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>misnomer</name>
	  <meaning>a name that is wrong</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A horseshoe crab looks more like a stingray than a crab: so the term 'horseshow crab' is a misnomer.</example>
	  <etymology>from the old French mesnommer: to misname, from mes: wrongly, and nommer: to name</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>misnomer</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>monoglot</name>
	  <meaning>speaking one language only</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As English is spoken the world over, most English people get away with being monoglot</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek monos: single, and glotta: tongue</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>monoglot</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>monolithic</name>
	  <meaning>(of an organisation or a building) very large and without quirks</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Chinese Communist Party plays down the importance of any one individual, reflecting its monolithic nature</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek monos: single, and lithos: stone; monolithic literally means 'formed of a single large block of stone'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>monolithic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>moratorium</name>
	  <meaning>a temporary ban of an activity</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With the world's supply of fish on the wane, governments agreed a moratorium on code fishing.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin moratorius: delaying</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>moratorium</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>mordant</name>
	  <meaning>(of humour) biting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The comments directed by Simon Cowell towards aspirant singers on his TV show The X Factor are full of mordant humour</example>
	  <etymology>from the French mordre: to bite</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>mordant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>multifarious</name>
	  <meaning>having many parts</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Catholicism and Anglicanism are two of the multifarious branches of the Christian faith.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin multifarious: manifold, combined with the Greek farius: showing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>multifarious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>munificent</name>
	  <meaning>particularly generous</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Robert Redford used his salary from Butch Cassidy and the Sundance Kid to set up the Sundance Film Festival for independent films: a munificent gesture.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin munificus: bountiful</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>munificent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>myopic</name>
	  <meaning>having no foresight</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Mike Tyson disconcerted Evander Holyfield by taking a bite out of his ear during their boxing fight; later, though, Tyson was disqualified, proving this was a myopic tactic.</example>
	  <etymology>"short-sighted," 1800, from myopia + -ic. Figurative use from 1891. Related: Myopical (1748); myopically.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>myopic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nativism</name>
	  <meaning>the policy of favouring the interests of native-born inhabitants above those of immigrants</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. There is a campaign on Facebook called 'People United Against Nativism' whose slogan is: 'nativism is so 19th century'</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the English word, native</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nativism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nebulous/amorphous</name>
	  <meaning>(of a shape) unclear</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jamie Oliver has never been filmed cooking in the nude, so the reasons for his being called The Naked Chef are nebulous/amorphous</example>
	  <etymology>nebulous derives from the Latin nebula: a cloud (nebulous literally means 'in the form of a cloud'); amorphous derives from the Greek amorphous: shapeless, from a: without, and morphe: form</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nebulous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nemesis</name>
	  <meaning>the punishment for excessive pride (see also hubris)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bernard Madoff showed hubris in believing he could deceive so many investors forever; nemesis came when his fraud was discovered he was imprisoned for life</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek nemesis: retribution</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nemesis</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>neologism</name>
	  <meaning>a newly invented word or expression</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The advent of the Internet led to neologisms such as 'to surf the net' which are now commonly used</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek neos: new, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>neologism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>netherworld</name>
	  <meaning>the part of society involved in crime</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Newspapers often report murders and other crimes; it seems that every type of netherworld is of interest to journalists</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English nether: lower, and world; netherworld literally means: 'the underworld of the dead'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nexus</name>
	  <meaning>a connection binding together two or more things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barack Obama has declared his intention to break the nexus between 'Big Oil' and politics</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin nex: bound, from nectere: to bind</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nexus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nimbus</name>
	  <meaning>a large rain cloud</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. I rushed home to grab an umbrella after I saw the nimbuses overhead</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin nimbus: cloud</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nimbus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>noblesse oblige</name>
	  <meaning>the responsibility of privileged people to show generosity to those less privileged</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Angelina Jolie does much charity work for landmine victims: she is a celebrity who exercises noblesse oblige</example>
	  <etymology>In his novel Le Lys dans la vallee (which translates as The Lily of the Valley), the 19th century French novelist Balzac summarises his advice to a rich young man by the two words: 'noblesse oblige!'. This phrase - which literally means 'nobility creates obligations' - is cited today as a reminder that, with great wealth comes great responsibility: the rich have a duty to help the poor. Today, we use the phrase noblesse oblige to remind someone who has enjoyed success that they should help others who have fared less well.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>noblesse-oblige</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nomenclature</name>
	  <meaning>the act of choosing names for things; OR the collection of names thus chosen</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To describe female acting professionals, the term 'actors' is now preferred to the original nomenclature of 'actresses'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin nomenclatura, from nomen: name, and clatura: calling (from calare: to call)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nomenclature</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>normative</name>
	  <meaning>establishing a rule or behaviour</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Marriage has a normative effect on society because it ensures communities are composed on tight-knit groups made up of parents and offspring.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin norma: a rule</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>normative</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>nostrum</name>
	  <meaning>a favourite but usually hopeless schema for effecting social improvement</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To stem rising numbers of single parent families and encourage more family units, John Major announced his nostrum: the Back to Basics campaign</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin nostrum: 'our own make' - a term used in ancient times by quacks claiming  special virtue for their own make of wares; a nostrum literally means 'an ineffective medicine prepared by an unqualified person'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>nostrum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>numinous</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the spiritual and the mysterious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the secular 21st century, art and literature have for many replaced religion as a means of accessing the numinous.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin number, numis: divine power</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>numinous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>obfuscate</name>
	  <meaning>to bewilder</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Literary novels sometimes fall to sell well because the average reader finds the complicated structure of such novels frequently obfuscates the story (if indeed there is one).</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin obfuscare: to darken; obfuscate literally means 'to make obscure'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>obfuscate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>oblique</name>
	  <meaning>not direct in dealing with a point</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Jeremy Paxman once asked Michael Howard the same question 12 times in a row because he was finding the politician's responses so oblique.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin obliquus: slanted; oblique literally means 'neither parallel nor at a right angle to a specified line'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>oblique</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>obscurantist</name>
	  <meaning>describes someone who casts a veil over the facts</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After a long period of being obscurantist on their interrogation methods, the CIA finally admitted it had used 'water-boarding' on terrorist suspects.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin obscurare: to make dark</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>obscurantist</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>obtuse</name>
	  <meaning>annoyingly slow to grasp (something)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Doctors must not allow themselves to be overly affected by human suffering: perhaps this is why they can appear obtuse to some patients.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin obtusus, past participle of obtundere: to beat against.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>obtuse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>oleaginous</name>
	  <meaning>obsequious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Tony Blair's friends describe him as charming, while his enemies call him oleaginous/unctuous.</example>
	  <etymology>oleaginous derives from oleaginus: of the olive tree, from oleum: oil (oleaginous literally means 'oily'); untuous derives from the Latin unguere: to annoint</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>oleaginous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>olfactory</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the sense of smell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To smell a bunch of flowers is an olfactory treat</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin olfacere: to smell</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>olfactory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>opaque</name>
	  <meaning>hard to make out</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Isaac Newton used to deliver lecture after lecture to empty rooms: jis pupils had all stopped turning up because they found his talks to opaque</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin opacus: darkened</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>opaque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>opprobrium</name>
	  <meaning>bitter criticism</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Homophobia attracts opprobrium in the West</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin opprobrium: reproach, from ob: against, and probum: disgraceful act</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>opprobrium</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ordure</name>
	  <meaning>something horrid</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Agatha Christie hated her fictional creation Hercule Poirot, calling him 'an egocentric creep' and referring to him as though he were ordure.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin horridus: horrid; ordure literally means 'excrement'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ordure</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ornery</name>
	  <meaning>ill-tempered</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Despite having a painful back which necessitated frequent operations, John F Kennedy never appeared ornery in public.</example>
	  <etymology>ornery is a 19th-century dialectical variant of 'ordinary'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ornery</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>orotund</name>
	  <meaning>(of a voice) full; OR (of writing) pompous</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Actor Laurence Olivier's voice used to fill any theatre: it was one of the most orotund in the business</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ore rotundo: with rounded mouth</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>orotund</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Orwellian</name>
	  <meaning>(of an authority) contrary to the welfare of a free society - as described by the novelist George Orwell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Belgian citizens are required to carry a national ID card at all times - an imposition which some describe as Orwellian</example>
	  <etymology>Orwellian means reminiscent of the works of George Orwell (1903-1950), particularly his novel Nineteen Eighty Four. In Nineteen Eighty Four, a civil servant called Winston Smith has the job of falsifying records to make it appear the government is always right. The term Orwellian is today used to describe any attempt by government to control individuals by similarly-doctored propaganda or by any other means, such as surveillance.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>orwellian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>outre</name>
	  <meaning>beyond the pale</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Outre comments by Jonathan Ross led to his suspension without pay by the BBC for 12 weeks in 2008.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French outre: exceeded, from the past participle of outrer: to exceed</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>outre</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>oxymoron</name>
	  <meaning>a phrase involving contradictory terms placed side by side to produce an amusing result</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Robin Hood stole from the rich but gave to the poor: you could call him 'an honest rogue' if you like that oxymoron</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek oxumoros: pointedly foolish, from oxus: sharp, and moros: foolish</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>oxymoron</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>palimpest</name>
	  <meaning>something that displays its past (as well as its present)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The police shone infrared lights inside Fred West's home, revealing palimpests of bloodstains that the serial killer had sought to wash away</example>
	  <etymology>palimpest literally refers to an ancient Roman manuscript on which the original writing had been rubbed away to make room for later writing (as was the Roman custom); hence the Greek etymology, palin 'again', and psestos: 'scraped' - so palimpest literally means 'scraped (clean and used) again'. However the original writing was not lost forever; with the passing of time, the faint outlines of the earlier writing would reappear with sufficient clarity for scholars to read it. Today, we use palimpest to describe an object that displays its past (as well as its present) - for example, our brain is the ultimate palimpest, retaining so much information about our past while also accounting for our present behaviour.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>palimpsest</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>palliative</name>
	  <meaning>relieving a problem without curing it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It is said that Queen Victoria used marijuana to relieve menstrual pain: the drug was her palliative of choice</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin palliatus: cloaked</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>palliative</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>panache</name>
	  <meaning>a flamboyant conviction in one's own sense of style</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The quality that makes Roger Federer so easy to watch as a tennis player is not his fitness or serve but his overall panache.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French panache, itself derived from the Italian pennachio: a plume of feathers</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>panache</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Panglossian</name>
	  <meaning>a person who is optimistic whatever happens</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The press depicted Gordon Brown as Panglossian in taking so long to acknowledge the UK was in the grip of a credit crunch.</example>
	  <etymology>Pangloss is a character in the novel Candide by Voltaire (1694-1778). He is a tutor charged with educating the young Candide, who lives in beautiful surrounds; Pangloss is an optimistic teacher whose mantra is as follows: 'all is for the best in the best possible of worlds'. Candide eventually leaves his pampered existence and witnesses such suffering in the world that he abandons  Pangloss's rosy world view in favour of his own pragmatic philosophy, which is: 'all you can do is tend your own garden'. Today, we continue to describe anyone who is excessively optimistic as Panglossian.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>panglossian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>panoply</name>
	  <meaning>an admirable collection of things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Actress Marlene Dietrich once wore a gown containing feathers from 300 swans: a panoply of plumage</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin panoplia: full armour, from the Greek panoplia: all, and hopla: arms</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>panoply</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pantheon</name>
	  <meaning>a group of illustrious people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Alfred Hitchcock never received an Oscar despite his undisputed place amongst the pantheon of film directors.</example>
	  <etymology>pantheon literally meant in ancient Greece 'a temple of all gods', deriving from the Greek word pan: all, and theos: god. Indeed the most famous such structure retains the word in its name: the Pantheon of Rome (built in 27BC). Since the 16th century the word pantheon has come to mean 'an exalted set of people'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pantheon</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>paradigm</name>
	  <meaning>a model</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Audrey Hepburn was the paradigm of success at a young age, winning an Oscar for her very first film, Roman Holiday.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek paradeigma: a model</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>paradigm</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>paragon</name>
	  <meaning>a person or thing viewed as a benchmark for others</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Christiano Ronaldo is one of the world's most expensive players because he is a paragon of footballing excellence.</example>
	  <etymology>paragon derives from the Italian word paragone, meaning 'a touchstone to test gold'. The touchstone in question was black quartz (a semi-precious mineral), which was used for testing the quality of gold alloys by rubbing them on it and then comparing the streak left behind by the gold alloy with a streak left by pure gold (which leaves a clear yellow line behind). Gradually paragon assumed its current figurative usage, referring today to a model of excellence by which other people or things must be judged. (See also touchstone, which has a near-identical meaning).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>paragon</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parenthetical</name>
	  <meaning>within (or as if within) a parenthesis, which is an explanatory phrase enclosed by curved brackets</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Conversations with Fidel Castro are reported to last for hours; presumably this is because the Cuban leader indulges in parenthetical asides when he talks.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek parentithenai: to put in beside</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parenthetical</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>par excellence</name>
	  <meaning>superior to others of the same kind</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. American financier Warren Buffett has won a reputation for being an investor par excellence</example>
	  <etymology>from the French par excellence: by excellence</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>par-excellence</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parlay (something) into (something more valuable)</name>
	  <meaning>to convert (something) into (something more valuable)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The young Sir James Goldsmith joined his brother in a pharmaceutical venture; from this he amassed a tidy sum which he went on to parlay into billions.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin par: equal</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parlay</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parlous</name>
	  <meaning>fraught with danger</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Gangster Al Capone's health was always in a parlous state due to his refusal to receive injections.</example>
	  <etymology>parlous is a Middle English contraction of 'perilous'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parlous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parochial</name>
	  <meaning>having a narrow world-view</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The British regard Americans as having a parochial world-view because less than one third of Americans have passports.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek paroikos: a neighbour</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parochial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>paroxysm</name>
	  <meaning>a sudden expression of an emotion; OR a sudden bout of a disease</meaning>
	  <example>e.g After his wife died in a plane crash, actor Clark Gable turned to drink in a paroxysm of grief.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek paroxusmos: a severe fit of a disease, deriving from para: (intensifying prefix) and oxunein: to sharpen</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>paroxysm</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parse</name>
	  <meaning>to examine (something) closely, especially by breaking it up into parts</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Scientists can easily parse the behaviour of chimpanzees into the conventional categories of human comportment.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin pars: part</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>parsimonious</name>
	  <meaning>frugal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Most of the world's religions advise the faithful to lead a parsimonious life</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin parsimonia: frugality</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>parsimonious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>paternalist</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the practice by rulers of limiting the freedom of those being ruled (purportedly for the good of the latter)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After Saddam Hussain's removal, the US waited for such a long time before allowing democratic elections in Iraq that accusations of paternalist behaviour abounded.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin pater: father</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>paternalist</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pathetic fallacy</name>
	  <meaning>the attribution in artistic works of human feelings to non-human things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Novelists are fond of using pathetic fallacy; an example can be found in the use of the expression 'the sky is weeping' instead of the more conventional 'it is raining'</example>
	  <etymology>pathetic fallacy is composed of the Greek word pathos, meaning 'the quality that arouses pity', and the Latin word fallere: to deceive. As a pathetic fallacy refers to depicting non-human things in a human light (which is a popular activity of artists), it is no surprise that it was an art critic. John Ruskin, who coined the term, noting in his book Modern Painters (1856) that the pathetic fallacy had as its aim 'to signify any description of inanimate natural objects that ascribes to them human capabilities...'. An everyday example of a pathetic fallacy is when someone looks up and says of the rain falling from above: 'the sky is weeping'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pathological</name>
	  <meaning>caused by a disease</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Sportsmen who reach world number one are usually pathologically competitive.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek pathos: suffering, disease, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pathological</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>patina</name>
	  <meaning>a surface that has changed due to age</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The face of a 90 year old is etched with a patina of fine lines and wrinkles</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin patina: a shallow dish (which is an example of a piece of crockery prone to incrustations caused by the passing of time)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>patina</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>patrician</name>
	  <meaning>belonging to an illustrious and wealthy family</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Daniella Steel has no need for the riches from her 580m book sales for she was born into a patrician family.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin patricius: having a noble father</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>patrician</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Pavlovian</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a response that, over time, can be elicited by one stimulus alone (when at first two stimuli were needed)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When I see my wife putting on her apron, I start salivating - before she has even touched any food - due to a Pavlovian response to that apron of hers</example>
	  <etymology>Pavlovian is an expression deriving from the work of Ivan Pavlov (1849-1936), a Russian scientist who won the Nobel Prize. Pavlov noted that dogs salivate when food is presented to them; far more significantly, he also noticed that - if you ring a bell seconds before presenting the food - eventually the bell alone will be enough to produce the salivation (even if no food is ever presented). Thus Pavlov concluded that some responses by an animal are based on that animal's previous experiences (and are not just based on an animal's reflexes). Today, we use the word Pavlovian to describe any response within us that we can only explain owing to a past experience coming to the fore (rather than owing to our reaction to a present stimulus outside of ourselves).
	  </etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pavlovian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pellucid</name>
	  <meaning>(of a concept) easily grasped</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ernest Hemingway wrote such simple sentences that his novels are considered amongst the most pellucid in the English language.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin perlucere: to shine through, from per: through, and lucere: to shine</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pellucid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>penitential</name>
	  <meaning>repentant</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Victims of fraudster Bernard Madoff were angry that he didn't appear more penitential in court</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin paenitentia: repentance</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>penitential</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>penurious</name>
	  <meaning>very poor</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. There are many charities set up in order to help penurious families</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin penuria: need</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>penurious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>perdition</name>
	  <meaning>hell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many people who start off by abusing soft drugs like marijuana end up in the perdition of heroin addiction.</example>
	  <etymology>(in Christian teaching) from the Latin perditio: ruin; perdition literally means 'utter rain'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>perdition</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>peremptory</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person's manner) insisting on total subservience</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Elvis Presley once insisted on flying 500 miles in his jet to collect a peanut butter sandwich; his staff complied, afraid to refuse his peremptory request</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin peremptorius: decisive, from perimere: to take away (from per: completely, and emere: to procure)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>peremptory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>perfunctory</name>
	  <meaning>(of an action) done carelessly, as a matter of routine</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Breakfast at Tiffany's author Truman Capote hated writing so postponed it by sharpening pencils for hours; he found this perfunctory action soothing.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin perfunctorious: careless</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>perfunctory</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>peripatetic</name>
	  <meaning>travelling around from place to place</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Richard Branson is a peripatetic man who seems as likely to be in a hot air balloon halfway across the Atlantic as he is to be in London.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek peripatetikos: walking about, from the verb peripatein: to walk about</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>peripatetic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>peroration</name>
	  <meaning>the final part of a speech (that is intended to inspire enthusiasm in the audience)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. David Cameron's speeches often culminate in a stirring peroration</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin perorare: to speak at length, from per: through, and orare: to speak</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>peroration</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>perspicacious</name>
	  <meaning>having a clear insight into things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Leonardo da Vinci was a perspicacious individual who was not just a painter but also the designer of several flying machines.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin perspicare: to see clearly, from per: through, and specere: to look</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>perspicacious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>phalanx</name>
	  <meaning>a group of similar-looking people or things</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Arthur Conan Doyle killed off Sherlock Holmes in his short story The Final Problem, a phalanx of grief-stricken fans wearing black armbands protested outside his home.</example>
	  <etymology>phalanx is an ancient Greek word used to describe a group of soldiers who formed a defensive unit by packing themselves tightly together, overlapping their shields and extending their spears. Today, we continue to use this word to describe any group of people who look the same and stay close together - such as photographers awaiting a celebrity at a film première, or bodyguards surrounding a president. This plural of this word is phalanxes. Note though that there is an alternative plural, which is phalanges - and this has a different meaning, which is 'bones of the finger or toe': e.g. If a footballer fractures his phalanges, he is out of action for weeks.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>phalanx</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>phantasmagorical</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a sequence of surreal images as if from a dream</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Lothario Errol Flynn observed that women would watch his films, create a phantasmagorical image of him, and then try a 'direct confrontation' with him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French fantasme: phantasm</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>phantasmagorical</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pharisaic</name>
	  <meaning>self-righteous and punctilious</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Politicians who denounce adultery while themselves having affairs are pharisaic.</example>
	  <etymology>The word pharisaic derives from the Pharisees, an ancient Jewish sect notorious for their strictness and sense of superiority. In the New Testament, the Pharisees are presented as rule-followers, in contrast to Jesus who is concerned only with expressing God's love. For example, the Pharisees ostracise sinners, whereas Jesus actively seeks them out. Today, we use the word pharisaic to refer to anyone who displays self-righteousness in their obsession with following the rules.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pharisaic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>phlegmatic</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) having a disposition that cannot be perturbed</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Dalai Lama has a permanent smile which gives him a phlegmatic air.</example>
	  <etymology>
	  Nowadays, phlegm is used to mean 'mucus discharged from the mouth'. However, the ancient Greeks used the word differently: for them, phlegm was one of four body fluids that account for our mood (the Greek word was phlegma, meaning 'an inflammation', reflecting the fact that phlegm was also supposed to be the cause of many diseases). Phlegm was believed to be associated with a calm, near apathetic, temperament. This sense persists in the meaning of the word phlegmatic today, which we use to describe someone who does not get rattled easily.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>phlegmatic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>physiognomy</name>
	  <meaning>a person's facial features, especially when regarded as reflecting that person's character</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Research shows aggressive people tend to have particularly wide faces (due to high testosterone levels): this is proof of the value of physiognomy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek phusiognomonia: judging of a man's nature (by his features), based on physio: nature, and gnomon: a judge.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>physiognomy</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>picaresque</name>
	  <meaning>relating to an episodic style of fiction dealing with the adventures of a dishonest but likeable hero</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn by Mark Twain can be described as a picaresque novel because it covers the life of a roguish hero of lowly social status who lives by his wits; The White Tiger by Aravind Adiga is a modern-day example.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Spanish, picaro: rogue</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>picaresque</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>plangent</name>
	  <meaning>(of a sound) like a lament</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. One billion people worldwide watched Michael Jackson's funeral, at which Stevie Wonder sung in plangent tones.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin plangere: to lament</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>plangent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pluralistic</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a system in which two or more groups live side by side</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Muslims live alongside Christians in Britain - proof that we live in a pluralistic society.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin plus, plur: more</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pluralistic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>plutocrat</name>
	  <meaning>a person whose power is due to their wealth</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Prime Minister of Italy, Silvio Berlusconi, is also a billionaire who controls several TV channels: hence his being labelled a plutocrat by journalists.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek ploutos: wealth, and kratos: rule</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>plutocrat</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>poleaxed</name>
	  <meaning>to have received a huge shock</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a child, horror writer Stephen King witnessed a friend being run over by a train: the experience left him poleaxed.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the word poleaxe: a short-handled axe with a spike at the back; poleaxed literally means 'as if struck by a poleaxe'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>polemic</name>
	  <meaning>a strong verbal assault on someone or something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After he was convicted of the rape of Desires Washington, Miss Black Rhode Island, the press launched a polemic against Mike Tyson.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek polemos: war</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>polemic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Pollyanna</name>
	  <meaning>a person who is overly optimistic</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Judy Garland got divorced from no less than four husbands but still decided to marry a fifth time: this undented optimism proves she was a Pollyanna.</example>
	  <etymology>Pollyanna originates from the name of the main character in Eleanor H. Porter's best-selling novel, Pollyanna, which was published in 1913. In the novel, Pollyanna, an orphan, goes to live with her austere aunt in a New England town in America. Pollyanna is an optimistic type who enjoys playing a game her father taught her, which involves trying to spot a good side to everything. Eventually her optimism proves infectious, transforming the town into a happy place. Today, we continue to describe anyone with such a relentlessly optimistic attitude as being a Pollyanna.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pollyanna</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>polyglot</name>
	  <meaning>knowing many languages</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rowan Williams, the Archbishop of Canterbury, talks with ease to the leaders of other world faiths because he is a polyglot.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek polu: many, and glotta: tongue</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>polyglot</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>polymath</name>
	  <meaning>a person who has much knowledge</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Leonardo da Vinci was not only a consummate painter, but he was also an inventor who designed military machines such as rapid-firing cannons: he was a true polymath</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek polumathes: having learned much, from polu: much (the stem of manthanein to learn)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>polymath</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>polyphonic</name>
	  <meaning>producing many sounds at the same time</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. At the age of two, Mozart paid a visit to a farm and, from amidst the polyphonic backdrop, identified a pig's grunt as being in G-sharp.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek poluphonos, from polu: many, and phone: voice</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>polyphonic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>popinjay</name>
	  <meaning>a vain person</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With his foppish outfits and tousled hair, Oscar Wilde was a clear example of a popinjay.</example>
	  <etymology>from the old French papegai: a parrot</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>popinjay</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>porcine</name>
	  <meaning>like a pig</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Dr Robert Atkins invented a low carbohydrate diet to rid himself of his own porcine appearance</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin porcinus: a pig</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>porcine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>portentous</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a warning that something bad is set to occur</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The chief executive addressed his staff in a portentous tone, not realising that most of them were uninterested in his message and in fact daydreaming.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin: an omen; portentous literally means 'constituting a portent or omen'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>portentous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>potico</name>
	  <meaning>a portico consisting of a roof supported by columns spaced out at regular intervals</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Royal Opera House in London has a façade consisting of a giant portico.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin porticus: porch</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>portico</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>portmanteau word</name>
	  <meaning>a word that has been created by blending the sounds and meanings from two or more words</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Brunch is a portmanteau word coined from combining the words breakfast and lunch</example>
	  <etymology>from the French poter; to carry, and manteau: coat; portmanteau literally means 'a large suitcase that opens into two hinged halves'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>portmanteau</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>potentate</name>
	  <meaning>a ruler, especially one who takes no account of other people's desire</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The cringe-inducing character played by Ricky Gervais in the TV show The Office is a potentate who is blind to his own flaws.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin potens: powerful</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>potentate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>prehensile</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person or animal) capable of grasping</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many bank directors responsible for the credit crunch continue to hang on to their seats with what George Orwell called 'prehensile bottoms'</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin prehendere: to grasp</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>prehensile</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>prelapsarian</name>
	  <meaning>in a pure and unspoiled state</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bankers often fondly remember their bonuses during prelapsarian years leading up to the Lehman Brothers' collapse.</example>
	  <etymology>prelapsarian derives from the Latin word lapsus and literally means 'before (pre) the Fall (lapsus)', referring to the passage in Genesis about the fall of humankind into a state of sin owing to Adam and Eve disobeying God by eating the apple in the Garden of Eden. Today, we use the word prelapsarian to evoke that period of our lives when a state of unspoiled innocence prevailed.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>prelapsarian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>presage</name>
	  <meaning>(of an event) to be an indication that another event will happen</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Frank Bruno's bizarre behaviour presaged his being diagnosed with bipolar disorder.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin praesagire: to forebode, from prae: before, and sagire: to perceive keenly</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>presage</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>prestidigitation</name>
	  <meaning>magic tricks involving sleight of hand</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his TV shows, Derren Brown demonstrates acts of prestidigitation.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French preste: nimble, and the Latin digitus: finger</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>prestidigitation</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>preternatural</name>
	  <meaning>beyond what is natural</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Simon Cowell, inventor of The X Factor, has a preternatural ability to provide the public with what it wants.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin praeter: beyond, and natura: nature</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>preternatural</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>priapic</name>
	  <meaning>relating to male sexual activity</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. On their marriage night, War and Peace author Leo Tolstoy forced his wife to read extracts from his diaries detailing his prior priapic experiences.</example>
	  <etymology>priapic derives from the name of Priapos, who was the Greek god of male genitalia and fertility. The Greek myth surrounding Priapos is a particularly salacious one and goes as follows. His mother, Aphrodite, when pregnant with Priapos, won a beauty competition. The goddess who lost out to Aphrodite was so annoyed that she proceeded to curse Aphrodite's son, Priapos - who was still in the womb - to be born with a foul mind. As a result, when Priapos emerged into the world, he had an erection that would never subside. Today, we continue to refer to oversexed males as being priapic.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>priapic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>primordial</name>
	  <meaning>(of a quality) so fundamental as to have existed from the start of time</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Any good ruler understands that his subjects require food and lodging, for these are mankind's primordial needs.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin primordialis: first of all, from primus: first, and ordiri: to begin</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>primordial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Procrustean</name>
	  <meaning>enforcing uniformity and stamping out individual quirks</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some people do believe in God but do not belong to a particular religion because they find the associated rules and regulations Procrustean.</example>
	  <etymology>Procrustean derives from the name of Procrustes, a torturer in Greek mythology. Procrustes would force his victims back to his house to try out his bed for size. If they were too long for the bed, he would chop their legs off; if they were too short, he would stretch their limbs. in the event that someone was the perfect fit for his bed, Procrustes had a differently-proportioned bed that he kept in reserve and would produce the one that was the worst fit for his victim, thus, guaranteeing some form of torture would ensue. Today, we call someone Procrustean if they try to fit people into excessively narrow limits with no regard for individuality.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>procrustean</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>profligate</name>
	  <meaning>ruinously extravagant</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. F. Scott Fitzgerald, author of The Great Gatsby, was so profligate that he would light his cigarettes with flaming five-dollar bills.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin profligare: to ruin</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>profligate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>proliferate</name>
	  <meaning>to increase quickly in number</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Pete Sampras won the US Open at the age of 19; from this point onwards, his list of Grand Slam wins proliferated rapidly.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin proles: offspring, and ferre: to carry</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>proliferate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>prolix</name>
	  <meaning>(of speech or writing) using too many words</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Legal contracts are often prolix and so send most people to sleep.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin prolixus: poured forth, from pro: outward, and liquere: to be liquid</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>prolix</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>promulgate</name>
	  <meaning>(of an idea) to make known far and wide</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The disciples found Jesus's sermons so compelling that they set out to promulgate his teaching.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin promulgare, from pro: out, and mulgare: to cause to come forth; promulgate literally means 'to milk'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>promulgate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>propagate</name>
	  <meaning>to cause to spread</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Actor Richard Gere propagates AIDS awareness around the world.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin propagare: to multiply from layers or shoots, from propago: a young shoot; propagate literally means 'to reproduce by natural processes from the parent stock'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>propagate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>propitious</name>
	  <meaning>indicating a fair chance of success</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bjorn Borg would sport a beard when playing at Wimbledon because he believed that not shaving was propitious.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin propitius: favourable</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>propitious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>proselytise</name>
	  <meaning>to convert (someone) from one belief to another</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Christian missionary work has as its main goal that of proselytising non-believers.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek proselutos: a stranger or convert</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>proselytise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>protean</name>
	  <meaning>able to transform easily</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The pop singer Madonna is a protean performer who undergoes frequent image transformations.</example>
	  <etymology>protean originates from the name of Proteus, a sea god in Greek mythology who could prophesy the future. People came from far and wide to ask Proteus about their fates. However, they were frequently disappointed, for Proteu's quirk was that he disliked being asked direct questions so much that he would change shape in order to confuse these inquisitors. Today, we still describe someone as protean if they have the ability to change rapidly.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>protean</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>prurient</name>
	  <meaning>having an unhealthy interest in sexual matters: or encouraging sexual matters</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Errol Flynn had an active love life and he called his autobiography My Wicked, Wicked Ways, knowing this title would appeal to his prurient fan base.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin prurire: to itch, long
	  </etymology>
	  <pronunciation>prurient</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>puckish</name>
	  <meaning>playful in a mischievous manner</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Ian Fleming, the creator of James Bond, also wrote Chitty Chitty Bang Bang and other books for children to indulge in his puckish side.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the Middle English puke: an evil spirit</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>puckish</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pullulate</name>
	  <meaning>to breed quickly; OR to be pulsing with life</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Immediately before a big match, ticket touts pullulate around football stadiums.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin pullulare: to sprout, from the diminutive of pullus: young animal; pullulate literally means 'to breed so quickly as to become common'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pullulate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>punctilious</name>
	  <meaning>showing huge attention to detail</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Kingsley Amis would often write 500 words in punctilious fashion before drinking at lunchtime.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French pointaille: detail</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>punctilious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>(purdah) go into purdah</name>
	  <meaning>to go into social seclusion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After allegations of his infidelity surfaced, Tiger Woods went into self-imposed purdah.</example>
	  <etymology>purdah originates from the Persian word parda, which means 'a curtain', reflecting the Hindu or Muslim practice of 'purdah', which involved hiding women from the view of men. 'Purdah' is achieved either by the separation of the sexes or by women covering themselves with a 'burqa', which is a long, loose garment that covers the body from head to toe. Today, we use the phrase go into purdah to describe any instance of social seclusion, an activity most often practised by privacy-seeking celebrities.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>purdah</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>purgative</name>
	  <meaning>ridding someone of unpleasant feelings</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who have received a shock often find alcohol a purgative.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin: to purify; purgative literally means 'having the effect of a strong laxiative'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>purgative</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>purple prose</name>
	  <meaning>prose that is excessively ornate</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Barbara Cartland might have shifted 500m copies of her romantic novels, but critics didn't like her writing, describing it as purple prose.</example>
	  <etymology>purple prose was term used by the Romans to describe fancy writing. The phrase came about because, in Roman times, purple dye was very expensive to manufacture because it necessitated the crushing of tens of thousands of molluscs (types of shellfish). Consequently, it was only the Emperor and the very wealthy who could afford purple garments. However, certain social climbers developed the habit of sewing small bits of purple onto their robes to give themselves a 'touch of class'. This activity was considered pretentious. In 65 BC, the poet Horace harnessed the negative connotations of the colour purple when he described pretentious writing as purple and this phrase is still used today.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>purview</name>
	  <meaning>the extent of the influence (of someone or of something)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many decisions carried out by the government are determined by ministers and do not come within the purview of the Prime Minister at all.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French purveu: forseen</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>purview</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>pusillanimous</name>
	  <meaning>timid</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The character of James Bond is that of the alpha male: when you are hunting down terrorists, no pusillanimous streak can be indulged.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin pusillanimous, from pusillus: very small, and animus: mind</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>pusillanimous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>putrefy</name>
	  <meaning>to rot, emitting an unpleasant smell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If you discard prawns in a dustbin, there is soon an overpowering smell of putrefying crusacea.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin puter: rotten</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>putrefy</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>quango</name>
	  <meaning>an agency that receives finance from a government while acting independently of it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The Press Complaints Commission (PCC) - to which the government has given the power to regulate all British newspapers - is a classic example.</example>
	  <etymology>quango is based originally on the 1970s' US acronym of 'qua(si) n(on) g(overnmental) o(rganisation).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>quango</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>quarry</name>
	  <meaning>the object of pursuit</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After meeting Victoria Adams at a charity football match, David Bechham made her his quarry and eventually married her.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French curee: quarry, a hunting term that referred to the refuse parts of a slain animal that were given to the hounds in its skin (curee being based on the French cuir, meaning 'skin').</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>quarry</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>quiddity</name>
	  <meaning>the 'whatness' or intrinsic nature of someone or something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Certain novelists are so skilful that the reader feels he understands the singular quiddity of the lead character of the book better than that of his real-life spouse.</example>
	  <etymology>from the medieval Latin quidditas: whatness, from quid: what</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>quiddity</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>quiescent</name>
	  <meaning>lying still</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Maltreated workers may stay quiescent for years but will eventually mount a strike.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin quisecere: to be still</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>quiescent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>quixotic</name>
	  <meaning>very idealistic and unrealistic</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It takes a quixotic individual - like actor Clark Gable - to believe in the institution of marriage sufficiently to attempt it six times.</example>
	  <etymology>quixotic derives from the name of Don Quixote, the hero of the famous 17th-century Spanish novel of the same name by the author Miguel de Cervantes. Don Quixote is a retired country gentleman who develops an obsession with tales of chivalry. Eventually he becomes delusional and, designating a neighbour as his squire and a farm girl as his ladylove, he embarks on a series of adventures. At the height of hos madness he attacks some windmills, believing them to be giants (Incidentally, this episode is the genesis of our modern-day expression 'tilting at windmmills', which means 'fighting an imaginary opponent'). Eventually he undergoes a return to sanity but is left feeling melancholic and dies a broken man. When we call someone quixotic, we mean they are like Don Quixote: full of grand chivalrous schemes but not living in the real world.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>quixotic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rabid</name>
	  <meaning>raving</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Militant atheists depict fundamental Christians as being rabid.</example>
	  <etymology>rabid derives from the Latin rabere, which means 'to rave', and literally describes an animal made raving mad by rabies. We use the word figuratively to refer to a human who is 'foaming at the mouth' as they insist that their beliefs are correct; hence rabid is often used to describe religious extremists.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rabid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>raillery</name>
	  <meaning>teasing of a light-hearted nature</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who are in a grumpy mood can respond badly to raillery.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French raillery: to rail</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>raillery</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rapacious</name>
	  <meaning>snatching</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Every year Arnold Schwarzenegger donates to charity his $175,000 salary as governor of California: he seems the opposite of a rapacious Hollywood star.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin rapacis: snatching.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rapacious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>realpolitik</name>
	  <meaning>a system of politics based on a practical - rather than a moral - approach</meaning>
	  <example>Before he became Prime Minister, the press often accused David Cameron of tailoring his views to suit public opinion and of other instances of realpolitik.</example>
	  <etymology>realpolitik refers to the implementation of a form of politics that is pragmatic - often at the expense of moral considerations. The first practitioner of realpolitik was Otto von Bismarck, Chancellor to Wilhelm I of the Kingdom of Prussia (a landmass covering parts of Germany and Russia); for example, keen to ensure the election of a Pope favourable to his own political aims, von Bismarck had no qualms about attempting to manipulate the Papal elections during the 1870s. Modern proponents include Richard Nixon who, for example, tolerated the human rights' violations of China as this meant greater global stability. Today, when we describe someone as practising realpolitik, we mean they are pragmatic - rather than principled - individuals; in other words, they are Machiavellian.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>realpolitik</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rebarbative</name>
	  <meaning>unpleasant-looking and aggressive</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Marlon Brando became depressed in old age, his weight ballooned and his appearance became rebarbative.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French se rebarber: to face each other 'beard to beard' in an aggressive fashion.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rebarbative</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>recalcitrant</name>
	  <meaning>refusing to cooperate with authority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Most men end up married despite initially feeling recalcitrant towards the institution.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin recalcitrare: to kick out with the heels, based on calx: a heel</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>recalcitrant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>recidivistic</name>
	  <meaning>(of a convicted criminal) tending to relapse into crime</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Although the outlaw Jesse James carried out numerous successful heists, he was never satisfied with his takings, which led him to his recidivistic behaviour.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin recidivus: falling back, from the verb recidere, from re: back, and cadere: to fall</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>recidivism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>recondite</name>
	  <meaning>not well known</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Schott's Original Miscellany is full of information of a recondite nature</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin reconditus: hidden</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>recondite</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>recusant</name>
	  <meaning>defying an authority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many teenagers object to eating meals at the dining table and are generally recusant.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin recusans: refusing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>recusant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>redound to</name>
	  <meaning>to contribute (to a person's reputation)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Salvador Dali would shave his armpits until they bled in the hope he'd appeal more to females; this act of masochism redounds to his reputation as a man who adored women.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin redundare: to overflow, from re: again, and unda: a wave</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>redound</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>refulgent</name>
	  <meaning>shining</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As Lorn Sugar's chauffeur pulled up outside the building, the car's metalwork was refulgent in the sunlight.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin refulgere: to shine out, from re: (an intensifying prefix) and fulgere: to shine</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>refulgent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>reliquary</name>
	  <meaning>a container for relics</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Before admitting they would never fit her again, the fat woman tried some outfits from her reliquary of 'thin' clothes.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French relique: relic</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>reliquary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rescind</name>
	  <meaning>to revoke (an arrangement)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Obama has rescinded some laws created by Bush</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin re: (an intensifying prefix), and scindere: to divide</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rescind</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>residuum</name>
	  <meaning>a thing that is left behind after a process</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Grace Kelly is dead but her residuum of films continues to exist.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin residuus: remaining</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>residuum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>retrousse</name>
	  <meaning>(of the nose) turned up</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rumours abounded that Michael Jackson had plastic surgery because the passing of the years saw his nose become increasingly retrousse</example>
	  <etymology>from the French re: back, and trousser: to turn</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>retrousse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rhapsodise about</name>
	  <meaning>to talk about a topic with great passion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It is obvious from interviews that Prince Charles is in love with his wife Camilla because he often rhapsodises about her.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek rhapsodos: a bard who recites poetry (literally meaning 'someone who stitches songs together'), from rhaptein: to stitch, and oide: song</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rhapsodise</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ribald</name>
	  <meaning>referring to sex in a funny but rude way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Frank Sinatra was popular with the ladies and, after a few drinks, would boast about his sexual exploits in a ribald way.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French riber: to indulge in licentious pleasures</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ribald</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rictus</name>
	  <meaning>a gaping grin</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In photos Bill Clinton always seems to have a cheery demeanour, which is largely due to his permanent rictus</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin rictus: a gaping of the jaws of an animal, from the past participle of the verb ringi: to gape</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rictus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>riparian</name>
	  <meaning>situated on a riverbank</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many paintings from the impressionist era feature couples picnicking against a riparian backdrop.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ripa: bank</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>riparian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rococo</name>
	  <meaning>ornate in a tasteless way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The press likes to depict the large houses of Premier League footballers as tasteless blends of rococo features.</example>
	  <etymology>rococo describes many different forms of art, including music, architecture and woodwork. The rococo movement reached its peak in 18th-century Continental Europe and was characterised in furniture design by ornate spiral lines - hence the word's etymology from the French la rocaille, which means 'a garden made of rocks' (another example of an elaborate man-made creation). Examples of rococo art include the Palace of Versailles and the music of Vivaldi. Today, we continue to describe any intricate artwork as rococo.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>rococo</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>roue</name>
	  <meaning>a sex-obsessed old man</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After his trial for relations with a minor, Error Fylnn attached this notice to his door: 'Ladies: be prepared to produce your birth certificate'. What a roue!</example>
	  <etymology>The word roue has an interesting story behind it: in 18th century France, men who consorted with much younger women were punished by having their backs broken over a wheel (une roue). Today, we continue to describe dirty old men as roues.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>roue</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>rumbustious</name>
	  <meaning>out of control</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Frank Sinatra was a hell-raiser who was famed for his rumbustious comportment.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Icelandic, ram: (an intensifying prefix), and bunctious: bumptious (which means 'self-assertive to an irritating degree')</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Ruritanian</name>
	  <meaning>an inhabitant of Ruritania, a fictional country used by politicians and lawyers to illustrate a hypothetical case - especially if a reall country would object to be used in the example being considered</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If France and Germany sign a security pact, this means these two countries will defend each other in case of attack by, say, the Ruritarians.</example>
	  <etymology>Ruritania was the name given by novelist Anthony Pope to a fictitious European country in his novel The Prisoner of Zenda (1894). Within literature, the word Ruritania has since been used to conjure up a fictitious country in Europe abounding with fairly-tale notions of chivalry and romance (as per Pope's novel). For example, Evelyn Waugh describes one character in his novel Vile Bodies as a sad 'ex-King of Ruritania'. Today, the fictional country of Ruritania is most often used in a more practical context: namely by politicians and lawyers to illustrate a hypothetical case - especially if a real country would object to being used in the example being considered.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ruritanian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>salient</name>
	  <meaning>prominent</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Thomas Jefferson was responsible for the invention of the coat hanger but he is remembered for being the US President because this is the salient fact of his life.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin salient: leaping (from the verb salire); salient literally means 'pointing outward'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>salient</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sangfroid</name>
	  <meaning>composure under pressure</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rugby star Jonny Wilkinson's sangfroid explains his ability to penalty kick under pressure.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French sang-froid: cold blood</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sangfroid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sanguinary</name>
	  <meaning>involving the spilling of much blood</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Vlad the Impaler (1431-1476) would murder his victims in particularly sanguinary ways as he liked to drink their blood after killing them.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sanguis, sanguinis: blood</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sanguinary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sanguine</name>
	  <meaning>optimistic</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After divorcing his fifth wife, actor Clark Gable was sanguine about his chances of finding love again: sure enough, he soon found wife number six.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sanguis, sanguinis: blood; sanguine literally means 'bloody in colour'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sanguine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sardonic</name>
	  <meaning>dourly cynical</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Comedian Lewis Grizzard once sardonically commented: 'Instead of getting married again, I'm going to find a woman I don't like and just give her the house'.</example>
	  <etymology>sardonic derives from the ancient Greeks' belief that eating a certain plant from the country of Sardo (which was the Greek's name for Sardinia) would cause facial contortions that resembled those of sardonic laughter; death usually followed. Today, we continue to use sardonic to mean 'grimly cynical'; and 'gallows humour' (i.e. humour arising from life-threatening situations) is one manifestation of a sardonic sense of humour.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sardonic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>saturnine</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) slow and dark (in colouring) and melancholic</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Henry VIII's weight gain in old age made him slow and depressed: he had become saturnine.</example>
	  <etymology>Saturnine derives from the medieval Latin Saturninus, which means 'of Saturn'. In medieval times, Saturn was considered by astrologers to be the coldest and darkest of the planets because it was thought to be the furthest from the sun. When we describe someone as saturnine today, we summon up these negative qualities.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>saturnine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>scabrous</name>
	  <meaning>indecent</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The media are fond of quoting John F. Kennedy's scabrous comment: 'If I don't have a woman for three days, I get terrible headaches'</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin scaber: rough; scabrous literally means 'covered with scabs'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>scabrous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>scatological</name>
	  <meaning>concerning excrement</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Although some adults find fart jokes amusing, most people outgrow their scatological sense of humour of their youth.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek skor, skatos: excrement, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>scatological</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>schadenfreude</name>
	  <meaning>the pleasure experienced when someone other that you has a mishap</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Emperor Nero's wife pointed out he was late for dinner, he kicked her to death; on hearing this news, not even her fiercest enemies felt schadenfreude</example>
	  <etymology>from the German Schaden: harm, and freude: joy</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>schadenfreude</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>scintilla</name>
	  <meaning>no more than a spark of a feeling</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. He may have started as the underdog in the Tory leadership race in 2005, but David Cameron's faith in his speech-making ability gave him a scintilla of hope.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin scintilla: spark</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>scintilla</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sclerotic</name>
	  <meaning>rigid, unable to adapt</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The marriage between Marie Antoinette and Louis XVI wasn't consummated until its seventh year: theirs was a sclerotic relationship.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek skleros: hard, sclerotic literally means 'becoming rigid'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sclerotic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>scrofulous</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a form of tuberculosis that produces glandular swellings; OR morally degenerate</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The squalid environment of some jails abroad can make the inmates scrofulous.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin scrofulae: a swelling of the glands (diminutive of scrofa: a sow, which was said to be subject to the disease)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>scrofulous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sedition</name>
	  <meaning>conduct inciting people to overthrow an authority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Hitler used force to quell sedition</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin seditio, from sed: apart, and itio: going (from the verb ire: to go)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sedition</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sedulous</name>
	  <meaning>showing diligence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Mother Theresa worked sedulously to alleviate the suffering of the poor.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sedulus: zealous</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sedulous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>segue</name>
	  <meaning>to make a smooth transition from one thing to another</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After retiring from acting, Paul Newman sequed successfully into the business world, creating a profitable empire from making cooking sauces.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian seque: follows</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>segue</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>seismic</name>
	  <meaning>of earth-shattering proportions</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The events of September the 11th, 2001 had a seismic impact on world peace for years to come.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek seismos: earthquake</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>seismic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>seminal</name>
	  <meaning>strongly influencing future developments</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After being rejected for a job at the Foreign Office, Ian Fleming decided to create his alter ego, James Bond: so this snub was the seminal moment in the spy's creation.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin seminalis, from semen: seed; seminal literally means 'relating to semen'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>seminal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>semiotics</name>
	  <meaning>the study of signs and symbols</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In the novel The Da Vinci Code, a professor of semiotics at Harvard uses his knowledge to solve a series of puzzles and unearth a conspiracy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek semeioun: to interpret as a sign</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>semiotics</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sententious</name>
	  <meaning>given to expressing pompous opinions</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When they preach to their congregation, priests must avoid sounding sententious</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sententia: opinion</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sententious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>seraglio</name>
	  <meaning>the harem in a Muslim palace</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. It would be no surprise to learn that Saddam Hussein's palace contains a seraglio</example>
	  <etymology>from the Persian saray: palace</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>seraglio</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>serendipitous</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the occurrence of events by chance and with a positive outcome</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. For his 12th birthday, Elvis Presley wanted a bike but his mother could only afford a guitar: this proved to be a serendipitous gift for someone as musically talented as 'The King'.</example>
	  <etymology>serendipitous derives from the title of The Three Princes of Serendip, the English version of a fairy tale published in Venice in 1557 and to which author Horace Walpole referred in a letter he wrote in 1754. In the story, the three princes had a habit of stumbling across good things, or, as Walpole put it: 'were always making discoveries, by accidents and sagacity, of things they were not in the quest of'. Today, we use the word serendipitous to describe any chance event with a similarly joyful outcome.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>serendipitous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Shangri-La</name>
	  <meaning>an earthly paradise that is a retreat from the confusion of civilisation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Oprah Winfrey lives on a huge California estate called 'The Promised Land', which overlooks the ocean: this is her own Shangri-La</example>
	  <etymology>Shangri-La is a fictional place described in the 1933 novel Lost Horizon by James Hilton. In the novel, Shangri-La is a paradise in Tibet enclosed by mountains; its inhabitants have a peculiarly long lifespan and barely display signs of ageing. Shangri-La is now used to denote any joyful land that is isolated from the outside world; it can also be used to denote a lifelong quest - fro example, for a man who is obsessed with becoming prime minister, this goal is his Shangri-La.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>shangri-la</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>shibboleth</name>
	  <meaning>a phrase or concept identified with a particular group</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. By using the shibboleth of a 'just war' to describe his invasion of Iraq, Tony Blair is attempting to frame his actions within a wider religious and historical context.</example>
	  <etymology>shibboleth originates from a particularly bloody account in the Old Testament. In the passage (Judges 12:6), the Gileadites are pursuing the fleeing Ephraimites, whom the Gileadites have just defeated in battle. To identify a man as an Ephraimite, the Gileadites would ask him to say the word shibboleth (which means 'an ear of corn' in Hebrew); the Ephraimites could not pronounce this word correctly because they lacked a 'sh' sound in their dialect. Ephraimites would therefore fail the pronunciation test and then be slaughtered. Today, shibboleth is used to describe any phrase particular to a narrow group of people (such as 'credit derivatives', a phrase only bankers would claim to understand) or an experience common to one group (such as circumcision in the Jewish faith).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>shibboleth</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sibilant</name>
	  <meaning>sounding like a hiss</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The phrase 'she sells seashells on the seashore' is particularly sibilant.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sibilare: to hiss</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sibilant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>simian</name>
	  <meaning>like a monkey</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Charles Darwin published his book On the Origin of Species in 1859, newspapers responded by printing cartoons of Darwin in a simian guise.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin simia: an ape</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>simian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>simpatico</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) likeable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Michael Parkinson was an effective chat show host because he put guests at ease with his simpatico manner.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian simpatico: sympathetic</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>simpatico</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>simper</name>
	  <meaning>to smile in a flirty fashion</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Julia Roberts became an international sex symbol due to her role in the film Pretty Woman (1990) in which she simpered continually at the camera.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German zimpfer: delicate</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>simper</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>simulacrum</name>
	  <meaning>a representation of someone or something (usually a poor representation)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The 2008 film of Brideshead Revisited was panned by critics as an inferior simulacrum of the book.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin simulacrum: a representation</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>simulacrum</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>slough off</name>
	  <meaning>to peel off (an old skin)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a result of his army service in Afghanistan, Prince Harry succeeded in sloughing off his 'playboy' image.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the Low German slu(we): peel</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>slough</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>smorgasbord</name>
	  <meaning>a wide range of something</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Baptism and confession are regarded by atheists as parts of a smorgasbord of religious superstitions.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Swedish smorgas: slice of bread and butter, and bord: table; a smorgasbord literally refers to a buffet offering a variety of foods.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>smorgasbord</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sobriquet</name>
	  <meaning>a nickname</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Owing to his command of language, novelist Henry James received the sobriquet 'the Master'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French sobriquet: a tap under the chin, from sous: under, and briquet: throat</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sobriquet</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sodality</name>
	  <meaning>a fraternity of people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The villains in Dan Brown's novel The Da Vinci Code are members of Opus Dei, a real-life Roman Catholic sodality.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sodalis: comrade</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sodality</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>soigne</name>
	  <meaning>maintaining a polished experience</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his heyday, actor Roger Moore was renowned for his soigne good looks.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French soigne: taken care of</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>soigne</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>solecism</name>
	  <meaning>(in speech) a grammatical error</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some people think it is a solecism to split the infinitive, such as in the phrase 'to work really hard'.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek soloikos: speaking incorrectly</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>solecism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>solipsistic</name>
	  <meaning>obsessed with one's own feelings</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Truman Capote so admired an article about himself that he wallpapered his flat with 500 copies of the magazine in question: how solipsistic of him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin solus: along, and ipse: self</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>solipsistic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sop</name>
	  <meaning>something given to pacify (such as a bribe)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Bankers, at government-supported banks, complain that plans to cut their bonuses are a sop to angry taxpayers, say critics.</example>
	  <etymology>A sop meant 'bread dipped in liquid' in Middle English. The current sense of sop as being something designed to pacify someone came from the epic poem The Aeneid, written by Virgil (70-19BC). At one point in the Aeneid, the hero Aeneas decides to enter the underworld to see his dead father. Aeneas consults the guardian to the underworld, a prophetess called 'the Sibyl'. Knowing that the underworld is patrolled by a monstrous dog 'the Sibyl' prepares a sop soaked in honey and drugs to stupefy this animal; the plan works and the sop renders the dog comatose. Hence, today, a sop continues to mean 'something given to pacify' and often describes a small thing done as a concession to appease someone whose main demands are not being met.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sop</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sophistry</name>
	  <meaning>the use of unsound arguments, especially with the intention of outwitting someone</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When clients asked fraudster Bernard Madoff about his investment strategies, Madoff would use complicated language and sophistry to confuse them.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek sophistes: a sophist (a person who reasons with witty but unsound arguments)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sophistry</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sororal</name>
	  <meaning>of or like a sister</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Tennis stars Venus and Serena Williams enjoy a healthy sororal rivalry.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin soror: sister</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sororal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>specious</name>
	  <meaning>seeming plausible, but actually incorrect</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Daniel Craig appeared as the new James Bond in Casino Royale, reports that Pierce Brosnan would continue in the role were proved specious</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin speciosus: fair</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>specious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>splenetic</name>
	  <meaning>bad-tempered</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Inspector Morse's perpetual whisky-induced hangover perhaps explained why he was so splenetic.</example>
	  <etymology>splenetic derives from the Latin word splen, which means 'spleen'. This is because the ancient Greeks believed that the spleen - which is an organ involved in the creation and removal of blood cells - produced black bile which could darken someone's mood. Today, we continue to describe someone as splenetic if that person is in a strop.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>splenetic</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>spoonerism</name>
	  <meaning>an error in speech when the initial sounds of two or more words are transposed, often to comic effect</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The teacher meant to say 'you have missed the history lectures' but it came out as 'you have hissed the mystery lectures'; the class erupted in laughter at this spoonerism.</example>
	  <etymology>spoonerism is a term that takes its name from an English clergyman and scholar called William Archibald Spooner (1844 and 1930). Reverend Spooner was notorious for confusing the letters at the start of adjacent words. For example, he is alleged to have said in church: 'The lord is my shoving leopard'. Today, we use the word spoonerism to describe any instance of someone confusing the letters at the start of adjacent words.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>spoonerism</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>stentorian</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person's voice) loud and strong</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Arnold Schwarzenegger was chosen to star in action films because of his muscular physique and stentorian voice.</example>
	  <etymology>stentorian derives from the name of a man called Stentor, who in Greek mythology was the herald for the Greek forces during the Trojan War. In his work The Odyssey, Greek poet Homer notes that the loudness of Stentor's voice was equal to that of fifty men combined; however, Stentor's voice was not louder that a god's and he shouted himself to death during an unsuccessful attempt to defeat the god Hermes in a shouting contest. Today, the adjective stentorian is used to describe someone with a booming voice.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>stentorian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>stucco</name>
	  <meaning>fine plaster used for coating walls or moulding into decorative features</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Hello magazine often features photos of footballers' houses that have been made ornate by the use of stucco.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old German stukki: a fragment</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>stucco</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Sturm und Drang</name>
	  <meaning>unpleasant emotional turbulence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. During their teenage years most people are prone to Sturm und Drang.</example>
	  <etymology>Sturm und Drang is a German expression meaning 'Storm and Stress'. The Sturm und Drang movement originated in Germany at the end of the 18th century and involves the venting of spleen and anguish; this was as a reaction against the rigidity of the rationalism imposed by the Enlightenment movement. The most famous piece of literature of the time was Goethe's Die Leiden des jungen Werthers (The Suffering of Young Werther), a novel which describes a man so lovelorn that he kills himself. Today, when we describe someone as suffering from Sturm und Drang, we mean they are in a state of unpleasant emotional turmoil.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sturm-und-drang</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>suborn</name>
	  <meaning>to bribe or otherwise persuade (someone) to commit a crime</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To achieve their ends, politicians in Africa are often accused of suborning public institutions such as the media.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin subornare: to incite secretly, from sub: secretly, and ornare: to equip</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>suborn</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sulphurous</name>
	  <meaning>erupting with anger</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his heyday, John McEnroe's sulphurous comments to referees made for great newspaper stories.</example>
	  <etymology>sulphurous literally means 'containing sulphur'; sulphur is a chemical with which gunpowder and other explosives are formed. So, when we describe someone as sulphurous, it means that person is about to explode with anger.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sulphurous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>superannuated</name>
	  <meaning>too old to be of use</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Though she is now in her 80s, the Queen continues to perform many duties with great efficiency: no one would say she is superannuated.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin super: over, and annus: year</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>superannuated</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>supercilious</name>
	  <meaning>behaving as though one thinks one is above other people</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Supercilious people have a manner that causes offence to others.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin superciliosus: haughty, from supercilium: eyebrow</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>supercilious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>supplicant/suppliant</name>
	  <meaning>(of a person) making a humble plea to a leader</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Spike Milligan once called Prince Charles a 'little grovelling bastard' on live TV as a joke; but it is clear from this that the comedian was no supplicant.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin supplicare: to implore</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>supplicant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>suppurate</name>
	  <meaning>to form pus</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some women who have breast augmentation operations experience suppurating wounds for days afterwards.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin sub: below, and pus, puris: pus</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>suppurate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>susurrate</name>
	  <meaning>to murmur softly</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Top judge by his manly appearance, you would expect footballer David Beckham to have a loud voice; yet in interviews he usually susurrates.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin susurrare: to murmur</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Svengali</name>
	  <meaning>a person who controls another</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Simon Fuller has managed the Spice Girls and other celebrities, which resulted in the press giving him the title of 'management Svengali'.</example>
	  <etymology>Svengali originates from the name of a character in the 1894 novel Trilby by George du Maurier. In the book, Svengali is a character who uses hypnosis to control the singing voice of a weaker character called Trilby. Today, when we call someone a Svengali, we mean they are similarly controlling of someone else - usually in a sinister way.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>svengali</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sybarite</name>
	  <meaning>a person who is overly fond of luxury</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Charlie Chaplin used to frequent a brothel called The House of All Nations, which was a popular haunt of wealthy sybarites.</example>
	  <etymology>sybarite literally means 'an inhabitant of Sybarus'; Sybarus was a city in Italy that existed in the 6th century BC. Owing to the fertility of the surrounding soil, the inhabitants of Sybarus were among the wealthiest people in the world and were renowned for pampering themselves: the city was sufficiently well off to install the first street-lighting system in history. Today, a sybarite is someone who has a fondness for sensory indulgence.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sybarite</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>sylph</name>
	  <meaning>a thin female</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Despite being over 50 years old, Madonna retains the appearance of a sylph as a result of her exercise regime.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Modern Latin sylphes: a spirit inhabiting the air; a sylph literally means 'an imaginary spirit of the air'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>sylph</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>symposium</name>
	  <meaning>a meeting to discuss one topic in particular</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Samuel Beckett, author of Waiting for Godot, could go for hours without saying a word: he was not someone to seek out at a symposium.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin symposiium from the Greek symposion: an occasion for drinking together, from sun: together, and potes: drinker</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>symposium</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>synaesthesia</name>
	  <meaning>the evocation of one sense by the stimulating of another sense</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Whenever I smell smoke from my uncle's pipe, I immediately think of my dead aunt playing the piano; this synaesthesia leaves me giddy.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek sun: together, and oesthesis: sensation</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>synaesthesia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>synapse</name>
	  <meaning>a connection between two nerve cells; to displace the beats in music so that strong beats become weak and weak beats become loud</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When a thought comes into our head, electricity travels across the synapses in our brain.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek sun: together, and hapsis: joining</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>synapse</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>syncopate</name>
	  <meaning>to shorten a word by dropping sounds in the word's middle</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. People who think they are amusing when they syncopate words (such as by pronouncing the south London suburb of 'Clapham' as 'Cl'hm') are in fact annoying.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin syncopare: to swoon</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>syncopate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>synecdoche</name>
	  <meaning>a figure of speech in which a part is used to allude to the whole, or the whole is used to allude to a part</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A thief notorious for his ability to pick pockets is often called 'Fingers', this term being a synecdoche for his body as a whole.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek synekdokhe: a receiving together, from syn: with, ek: out, and dekhesthai: to receive (related to dokein: to seem good)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>synecdoche</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tabula rasa</name>
	  <meaning>the mind before it has been imprinted with the effects of experience</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The brain of a baby is a tabula rasa on to which the baby's parents etch their values.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin tabula: tablet, and rasa: erased</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tabula-rasa</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tangential</name>
	  <meaning>digressing from a prior course</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Cameron and Osborne arranged a dinner to discuss the economy but ended up discussing tangential matters.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin tangere: to touch; tangential literally means 'touching at a point without intersecting'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tangential</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>Tartuffe</name>
	  <meaning>a hypocritical pretender to any kind of superiority</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. J. Edgar Hoover, the first director of the FBI, called Playboy readers 'moral degenerates'; but he was a Tartuffe because he regularly watched pornographic films.</example>
	  <etymology>Tartuffe is the lead character in the play Tartuffe, written by the French playwright Maliere n 1664. In the play, Tartuffe persuades the other characters that he is pious and devout, whilst he is actually lustful and grasping. This rank hypocrisy is eventually revealed to all in the closing scenes.  Today, we call someone a Tartuffe if that person is a hypocrite of the highest order.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tartuffe</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tautology</name>
	  <meaning>expressing the same concept twice using different words (considered to be at fault of style)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The phrase 'frozen ice' is a tautology: all ice is frozen so there is no need for the adjective 'frozen'</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek tauto: same, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tautology</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tawdry</name>
	  <meaning>sordid and unpleasant</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Many a glamour model has been paid a small fortune by the media to give a tawdry account of an affair with a married footballer.</example>
	  <etymology>tawdry is a contraction of the name of Saint Audrey, an Anglo-Saxon saint. In the 17th century, devotees of Saint Audrey staged an annual fair where lace clothes would be sold. However, Puritans consider lace to look seedy and so it was that Saint Audrey - and the word tawdry that is a contraction of her name - became associated with tackiness. Today, we use tawdry to describe something that is sordid and cheap.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tawdry</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>teleological</name>
	  <meaning>relating to the explanation of living things by the purpose they serve rather than by their origins</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Religious people believed that our lives are subject to a teleological framework.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek telos: end, and logos: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>teleological</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tendentious</name>
	  <meaning>marked by a strong point of view, implicitly expressed</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The BBC is required to produce programmes that have no political or other agenda, so there is no tendentious editing at the Beeb.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Medieval Latin tendentia: a cause, from the Latin tendere: to stretch.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tendentious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tenebrous</name>
	  <meaning>shadowy</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his youth, Sean Connery worked as a coffin-polisher in a tenebrous building occupied by a funeral director.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin tenebrae: darkness</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tenebrous</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tenet</name>
	  <meaning>a principle</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. That Muhammed received a series of revelations from God is one of the main tenets of Islam.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin tenet, which means 'he holds', from the verb tenere: to hold</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tenet</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>termagant</name>
	  <meaning>a scolding woman</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Kathrine Hepburn would insist on sniffing the hair of her co-stars to make sure it was clean: such intrusive behaviour is typical of a termagant.</example>
	  <etymology>termagant was the name of a character in medieval morality plays. Termagant was a fictitious male Muslim deity with a violent nature who appeared in medieval morality plays. As Termagant wore long gowns, English audiences mistakenly believed the character was female. Today, when we call a woman a termagant, it means she has a scolding nature.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>termagant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>theocrat</name>
	  <meaning>a leader who rules in the name of God</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Until Japan's defeat in World War II - when Emperor Hirohito was forced to deny that the Emperor of Japan was divine - Japan was rules by theocrats.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek theos: god, kratos: rule</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>theocrat</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tinnitus</name>
	  <meaning>a ringing sound in the ears (often caused by a specific condition such as a head injury)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After leaving a loud pop concert, people often have tinnitus in both ears.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin tinnire: to ring, tinkle</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tinnitus</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tithe</name>
	  <meaning>ten percent of someone's income that is contributed to the Church</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Hundreds of years ago, most Christians paid the tithe; now very few do.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Middle English tithe, from the Anglo-Saxon tien: ten</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tithe</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>topography</name>
	  <meaning>the way the physical features of an area are arranged</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The SAS troops needed to become familiar with every nook and cranny of Pakistan so they spent months studying the country's topography.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek topographia, from topos: place, and graphe: writing</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>topography</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>totalitarian</name>
	  <meaning>a person advocating a dictatorship that requires total submission to the state</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. World leaders hope the openness displayed by China at events such as the Olympics is a sign that the government is relaxing its totalitarian stance.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin totus: whole, entire</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>totalitarian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>totemic (of)</name>
	  <meaning>markedly symbolic (of)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. For most people the Queen is the totemic member of the Royal Family.</example>
	  <etymology>totemic finds its root in the French word aoutem, which means an object considered by Indians to be the emblem of a clan. Totems were usually an animal or an object from nature; as well as being representative of a clan, totems were believed to protect the clansmen. Today, when we describe a person or thing being as totemic, we mean that it is distinctly symbolic of something.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>touchstone</name>
	  <meaning>a benchmark by which something is judged</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Roger Federer holds more Grand Slam titles than any other player in the history of tennis; his achievement is the touchstone for all future players.</example>
	  <etymology>A touchstone refers to a piece of dark jasper which was used to test the purity of a gold alloy by observing the colour of the mark the alloys made on it. The streak left behind was compared to the clear yellow streak left by pure gold. Today, we call something a touchstone when it provides a standard by which to judge other things. (see also paragon, which has a near0identical meaning).</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>touchstone</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>transmogrify</name>
	  <meaning>to transform, especially in a way that is not expected</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When he invented Facebook, Marc Zuckerberg was transmogrified fro mHarvard postgraduate to the youngest self-made billionaire on the planet.</example>
	  <etymology>deriving from the verb transmigrate: (of the soul) to pass into another body after death/</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>transmogrify</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>trenchant</name>
	  <meaning>(of language or a person) incisive and cutting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When people talk about failed romantic relationships, their tone of voice often becomes trenchant.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French trenchant: cutting, from the verb trenchier, itself based on the LAtin, truncare: to maim</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>trenchant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>triumvirate/troika</name>
	  <meaning>a group of three people working alongside each other</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A triumvirate/troika of film moguls - Spielberg, Geffen and Katzenberg - set up the studio  Dreamworks.</example>
	  <etymology>triumvirate derives from the Latin trium virum, the genetive plural of tres viri: three men; troika derives from the Russian troe: set of three. The so-called First Triumvirate was an informal political alliance of Julius Caesar, Pompeius Magnus ("Pompey the Great") and Marcus Crassus. The arrangement had no legal status, and its purpose was to consolidate the political power of the three and their supporters against the senatorial elite. After the death of Crassus in 53 BC, the two survivors fought a civil war, during which Pompey was killed and Caesar established his sole rule as perpetual dictator. The Second Triumvirate was recognized as a triumvirate at the time. A Lex Titia formalized the rule of Octavian, Mark Antony, and Marcus Aemilius Lepidus. The legal language makes reference to the traditional tresviri. This "three-man commission for restoring the constitution of the republic" (tresviri rei publicae constituendae) in fact was given the power to make or annul law without approval from either the Senate or the people; their judicial decisions were not subject to appeal, and they named magistrates at will. Although the constitutional machinery of the Republic was not irrevocably dismantled by the Lex Titia, in the event it never recovered. Lepidus was sidelined early in the triumvirate, and Antony was eliminated in civil war, leaving Octavian the sole leader.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>triumvirate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>trope</name>
	  <meaning>a common theme; OR the use of words in a non-literal way, such as a metaphor</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Much of the tension in the horror film The Shining derives from the trope of the psychic child who has the ability to foresee imminent evil.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Greek tropos: turn, way</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>trope</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>truculent</name>
	  <meaning>quick to fight</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Actor Errol Flynn blew the money he had saved for an engagement ring at the bookies; his truculent fiancée broke up with him as a result.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin trux, trucis: fierce</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>truculent</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>turpitude</name>
	  <meaning>corruption</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The US government still bars from entering the country those people considered to be in a state of moral turpitude.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin turpis: disgraceful</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>turpitude</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>tussock</name>
	  <meaning>a small patch of grass that is longer than the grass surrounding it</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. If you have mowed your lawn properly no tussocks will remain.</example>
	  <etymology>tussock derives from a 16th-century alternation of 'tusk', which meant a 'tuft'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>tussock</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>ululate</name>
	  <meaning>to utter howling sounds</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. During the funeral scenes in the Godfather films, old women in black ululate around the coffin.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin ululare: to howl, shriek</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>ululate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>utilitarian</name>
	  <meaning>useful, rather than beautiful</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Although most fridges are not beautiful, they are utilitarian.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin utilis: useful</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>utilitarian</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>utopia</name>
	  <meaning>an imagined place in which everything is in perfect harmony</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Kristen Scott Thomas's father was a Royal Navy pilot; when he died in a flying accident, this shattered the utopia of her childhood.</example>
	  <etymology>utopia has a rather depressing etymology - for it derives from the Greek words ou (meaning 'not') and topos (meaning 'a place'): in other words, a utopia or a sense of happiness is a place that does not exist. The word utopia was popularised by Sir Thomas More (who was beheaded by Henry VIII). In Of the Best State of a Republic and of the New Island Utopia (1516), More depicts the island of Utopia as a landmass where harmony reigns thanks to its perfect social and political structure. Today, we continue to refer to any perfect place as being a utopia. (For the opposite of a utopia - i.e. a place where discord reigns - see dystopia)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>utopia</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>uxorious</name>
	  <meaning>(of a husband) displaying an indulgent fondness for one's wife</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. On the TV show Richard and Judy, Richard's constant attention to his wife Judy gave the impression of an uxorious man.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin uxor: wife</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>uxorious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vagabond</name>
	  <meaning>a person without a home who wanders around</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. After his widowed mother was certified insane, Charlie Chaplin left school to join a dance troupe and become, in effect, a vagabond.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vagari: to wander</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vagabond</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vagaries</name>
	  <meaning>unforeseen changes in a situation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Winston Churchill often felt the urge to throw himself off railway platforms because he was prone to the vagaries of manic depression.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vagari: to wander</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vagary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vainglorious</name>
	  <meaning>characterised by vanity and boasting</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Some religious people regard atheists as being vainglorious for denying the existence of God.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French vaine gloire: vain glory</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vainglorious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>valedictory</name>
	  <meaning>serving as a farewell</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In his final months in office, Tony Blair appeared on several TV chat shows in a kind of valedictory tour.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vale: goodbye, and dicere: to say</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vainglorious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vampish</name>
	  <meaning>relating to a woman who uses sexual attraction to manipulate men</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The nature of the relationship between John F. Kennedy and Marilyn Monroe was clear from the vampish way in which she sang: 'Happy Birthday, Mr President'.</example>
	  <etymology>vampish derives from an early 20th-century abbreviation of 'vampire'</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vapid</name>
	  <meaning>dull, unstimulating</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. The piped music played in aeroplanes awaiting take-off invariably is vapid.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vapidus: flat</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vapid</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vaudeville</name>
	  <meaning>a stage play on a frivolous theme with songs along the way</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Musicals such as Mary Poppins owe a lot to the tradition of vaudeville, a theatrical genre of variety entertainment popular in the US until the 1930s.</example>
	  <etymology>vaudeville derives from the French word vaudeville, which in the 15th century meant 'a popular song'. (The word vaudeville's formation in France can be traced to the most famous writer of such songs who lived in the valley of Vire, or, in French, the Vau de Vire). It was variety theatre owners in the US who adapted the expression vaudeville at the end of the 19th century in the hope that the Frenchness of the term might lend the halls an air of sophistication and thus differentiate them in the public's mind from the earlier variety halls which were marked by rowdiness. Today vaudeville refers to any entertainment made up of a series of short musical sketches and with a light-hearted theme.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vaudeville</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>(much) vaunted</name>
	  <meaning>much praised</meaning>
	  <example>When Charlie Chaplin came third in a Charlie Chaplin lookalike contest, he had to admit that the winner, a much vaunted lookalike, did bear an uncanny resemblance to him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French vanter: to praise, based on the Latin vanitare: to talk frivolously (from the Latin vanare: to utter empty words, from vanus: empty)</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vaunted</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>venal</name>
	  <meaning>being open to bribery</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. One months before the invasion of Iraq, Saddam Hussein made an offer to stand down peacefully in return for $1bn; he remained venal to the last.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin venum: thing for sale</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>venal</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>venial</name>
	  <meaning>(of a fault) trivial</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Russian monarch Ivan the Terrible, who used to roast humans alive, regarded his other pastimes - such as throwing dogs off towers - as no more than venal sins.</example>
	  <etymology></etymology>
	  <pronunciation>venial</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>verbiage</name>
	  <meaning>writing that uses an excessive amount of words</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Walt Disney often spoke about the need for cleanliness; proving his words were no mere verbiage, he would wash his own hands up to 30 times an hour.</example>
	  <etymology>from the French verbe: word</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>verdant</name>
	  <meaning>(of countryside) green with grass or other organic matter</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. A team of gardeners ensure the lawns of Buckingham Palace remain verdant at all times.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old French verdoyant: becoming green, based on the Latin, virdare: to grow green.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>verdant</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vernacular</name>
	  <meaning>the everyday language spoken by the people in one region</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Anti-Muslim attitudes are commonplace; this is reflected by the fact that the word 'Islamophobia' has entered the English vernacular.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vernaculus: native, from verna: home-born slave</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vernacular</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vicarious</name>
	  <meaning>feelings experienced in one person's mind via someone else's descriptions or display of their own feelings</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Fred Astaire's dancing prevented him from watching his beloved soap operas, he would phone his housemaid to experience the plot twists vicariously.</example>
	  <etymology>vicarious originates from the word 'vicar': both words are derived from the Latin vicarius, meaning 'substitute'. In the Catholic Church, a vicar is the 'representative' of a bishop; similarly, when a fried tells us a story about his recent car crash, our friend becomes our 'representative' during the moments that the vehicle crumpled, and we experience the crash vicariously.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vicarious</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vicissitude</name>
	  <meaning>an unpleasant change in a situation</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When his wife died in a plane crash, Clark Gable kept her bedroom exactly as it was the day she caught the plane because he was so upset at this vicissitude.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vicissum: by turns.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vicissitude</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vilify</name>
	  <meaning>to talk about (someone) in a denigrating manner</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When Roger Clinton, half-brother of Bill, pleaded guilty to cocaine distribution, the press vilified him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vilis: of low value</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vilify</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>visceral</name>
	  <meaning>perceived as if in the internal organs (the viscera)</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. To fall in love at first sight is to experience an immediate visceral response to someone.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin viscera: the internal organs</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>visceral</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vista</name>
	  <meaning>a distant view especially one seen through an opening</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Dying of cancer in Switzerland, Audrey Hepburn had her bed positioned so she could see the mountains outside her window; she loved this vista.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Italian visto: seen, past participle of vedere: to see (from the Latin videre: to see); a vista literally means: 'a pleasing view seen through a long, narrow opening'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vista</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vitiate</name>
	  <meaning>to harm the quality of</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Told he was too sane for a psychiatric hospital, Spike Milligan stabbed Peter Sellers; in this way he vitiated his record of sanity and was admitted.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vitare: to impair</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vitiate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vituperate</name>
	  <meaning>to speak very disparagingly about someone</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When the 54-year-old Charlie Chaplin married the 18-year-old Oona O'Neill, the press vituperated him.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vituperare: to disparage</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vituperate</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>voluptuary</name>
	  <meaning>a person devoted to self-indulgence</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. As a voluptuary, Oscar Wilde loved sensual indulgence, especially an activity he called 'feasting with panthers', which meant going with rent-boys.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin voluptas: pleasure</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>voluptuary</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>vulpine</name>
	  <meaning>like a fox</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Alsatians are the most vulpine of dogs.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Latin vulpes: a fox</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>vulpine</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>wainscot</name>
	  <meaning>an area of wooden panelling running along the bottom of some walls</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Rooms in Victorian houses often have wainscot on the lower part of the walls of rooms.</example>
	  <etymology>from the medieval Flemish waghenscote: superior quality oak wood.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>wainscot</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>wanderlust</name>
	  <meaning>a yearning to travel</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Graham Greene wrote novels set on several continents, all of which he had travelled across to sate his wanderlust.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German wandern: to wander, and lust: lust</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>wanderlust</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>wanton</name>
	  <meaning>(especially of a woman) sexually indecent; OR (of an action) deliberate and out of the blue</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When he was just 18, William Shakespeare married a woman who was already clearly pregnant, leading to gossip accusing her of wanton behaviour.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Middle English wan: wanting, lacking, and togen: to discipline: together these words imply a notion of 'badly disciplined/badly brought up'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>wanton</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>waspish</name>
	  <meaning>very irritable</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When working as a librarian, the poet Philip Larkin would ask people in a waspish tone: 'Why on earth are you borrowing drivel like that?'</example>
	  <etymology>from the word wasp, an insect renowned for its irritability.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>waspish</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>wend</name>
	  <meaning>to travel slowly towards a particular goal</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. When exploring a new city, tourists are in no rush, usually preferring to wend their way around.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German wended: to turn</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>wend</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>wheedle</name>
	  <meaning>to convince someone using flattery</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. In 'honey-trap' operations, female police officers use their wiles to wheedle information out of male murder suspects.</example>
	  <etymology>from the German wedeln: 'to wag the tail like a fawning dog', hence 'to fawn, flatter'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>wheedle</pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>widow's peak</name>
	  <meaning>a V-shaped growth of hair in the centre of the forehead left behind as the hairline recedes</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. With age, men often develop a widow's peak.</example>
	  <etymology>widow's peak derives from the old wives' tale that a V-shaped hair pattern on a man's forehead means he will die soon, leaving his wife a widow.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation></pronunciation>
  </word>
  <word> 
	  <name>winnow (down)</name>
	  <meaning>to reduce the number (in a collection of things) until only the best ones remain</meaning>
	  <example>e.g. Every year 128 tennis players compete in the men's singles at Wimbledon; by the day of the finals their number has been winnowed down to just two contestants.</example>
	  <etymology>from the Old English windwian: to ventilate, from wind: wind; the literal meaning of winnow is 'to blow a current of air through (grain) in order to remove the chaff'.</etymology>
	  <pronunciation>winnow</pronunciation>
  </word>
</dictionary>
